Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the ask
show. Today I'm doing this on Monday
because yesterday there was a cricket
match that everybody wanted to watch and
it did not make sense to go live
yesterday. So I am doing this today and
welcome to all of you. Good evening to
those of you who are in the evenings for
whom it is evening and good day to those
of you who are somewhere where there's a
date where it's daytime and I'm going to
take questions today from the super chat
and live chat as as many as possible.
Right? So before we get into it let's
see who is there on the live chat. Today
is an unusual day Monday not Sunday. So
let's see who is there. I can see Katos
Ariasi
Shivasai GV V2
L Anikit Aniket is there. Who else do we
have? Baskar Bandit. Hello Anik once
again. Ritik Paw, Geopolitical Dubai is
here from Indor. Good to see you as
always. Honey Sharma. Um Hani Sharma is
also here. Incredible. Adwit Ashwani
Hani Sharma once again the only mighty
warrior. Basar Bandit once again. Honey
Sharma SK SKR7733
Har Banana Higard
Rei now Miss Patel Subg Kushal Mangal
yes indeed sub Kusha Mangal Vikash PJ
Baskar Bandit Har as well once again
Rohan Biri Mandatram sir Nirana Shanks
Kodin Shiva Kodi Chiva Somi hello uh
Baskar Bandit is here from Moscow good
evening to you sir go to U Ram Ram subco
yes indeed
Pratik Vora Adbat Ashmani Abishek Shukla
live India won. India won. Well, big
surprise here. I mean, was it even a
contest? I mean, if you look at the
result, it was exactly as expected. So,
India won. Yes. Outstanding. Brave robot
says, "Time to cook dinner. It's it's
ramen time." All right. Tech G78807
is here from Delhi. Hello. Mac 4 Janu
Namaskar. Tam Tanesh Pandi. Hello.
General Subutai. Hello. Uh Swami is here
from Jaipur. History G O T H L N N N N N
N N N N N N N N N N N N N N N D D D D D
D D D D D D D D D D D D D D D D T Patil
Namaste G Rahul is also here with an
interesting surname. Okay. Cast Jana.
Kastana. Hi. Random skull. Jri Krishna.
Good to see you sir. Random skull. Akash
not zul 7138.
Hi. Anand pai. Namaskar.
Swami says have I seen silence of the
lambs? Yes, I've watched it. Yes, good
movie. Meteor smasher. Namaskarum
indeed. Agam senpai. Amisha. Good
evening ma'am. Good to see you. Kushbu
art. Namaskar. Humanity survives. Did I
watch the match? Says humanity survives.
I I saw some portions of it near the end
and it was not even a contest. Hope.
Yeah. Anyway, good result for India of
course and no surprise. Pandu rang
ruler. Namaste. Go to uh Dashan Patel.
Namaste G. Namaste. Happy Monday. The
only mighty warrior. So good to see you
as well. Uh real bad Jam G. Ah Shuklive
is here from Kpur. Hi on hope. Priyanka
Javala. Namaste ma'am. Namaste. Abishek
Bardaj. Hello. Vishal Patro. Namaskar.
Tech G is here from Delhi. Nodzul Sumit
Z4 I9X.
Good evening. Good evening to you. Swami
Vikash PJ Blue Guy07. Hello. Uh Dashan
Patel the only mighty warrior global
citizen say 2862.
Thank you so much sir. Global citizen G.
Thank you so much. Very nice. Very nice
of you. Thank you so much. Ritij Pranam
G Chan Priya good evening ma'am good
evening. Ashley Moody is saying says
listening while working 16:32 in the
afternoon here. Well from Twitter. Thank
you so much. Uh Dak Ram Ram sir Shiv
Shivang Sharma Vikas PJ Mahishta hello
Viprit hello Dashan Patel Nudzul Shady
Coster ZSF no likes given
Saturday is here. Rit Nishant Sharma
Jham Nul is here from Pakistan. Good
evening to you sir from Pakistan to
Pakistan right. Vibri Shivang Sharma
Dashan Patil Akil
Pratam Kalawia hello uh and so many
other people. Manish Gi Namaste. Namaste
ma'am. Lalit tan namaste G. A Vanish is
also here. Takina is here from Dadun.
Good evening to you. Good to have you
from Dadun. Uh toxic Katos says did I
watch Knights of Seven Kingdom? Night of
seven kingdoms. I haven't seen that. Mi
Meit Raj Singh Chadasa. Namaste. Hello.
Basar bandit once again and everyone
else. Okay. Okay. Tech G Omar Kumbar
Hatim Electric Walla. Hello Vihankuran.
Good evening Jotumar Namaste Gul Namaste
Pram
Sahil Das Gupta Skype the Skype Prime
Namaskar okay so let's get going with
some questions Nikesh Dahal also is here
namaste
adila
okay omar sahil das Gupta from Kolkata
okay what what questions do we have
let's get going with some questions
Aryaasi says some kings in Rejewish
Israel had mitani inspired Arian names.
Okay. Search Marwan, Kilani, Amara,
letters, local rulers research paper
like Indar, Indaruta, Surat, Surata,
Maranu, warriors, etc. And let me know
if you need the PDF. Well, let's quickly
take take a look at this. It's an
interesting um uh data point here that
we have. So mari
ama letters
letters local rulers
what do we have uh is this one naming
practices and identity in the early late
bronze age Dr. Marwan Kilani
uh Marwan Kilani
this is about multiple names of local
rulers are attested in the amarna
letters of course armana amarna letters
are diplomatic correspondence between
the Egyptian pharaohs and various local
regional rulers
um linguistically west symmetic huran or
indooran the names have been variously
discussed and so on okay so that's uh
that what do we have here journal of
ancient Egyptian interconnections
once again by uh professor Marwan Kilani
it's the same paper I could download the
full text but we will not do that right
now and so on so looks like we have some
interesting revelations over here so
what we are talking about is pre-Jewish
Israel that's an interesting thing yeah
so what part of the world are we
referring to we're talking about the uh
the 11th right over here so let's go
there we're talking about the region
that is you know the the eastern
seabboard support the east east coast of
the Mediterranean region. Um this region
here which includes today's Israel,
Lebanon, uh western Syria, the west
coast of Syria and so on. That's the
region we're talking about. And if you
go north of that, if you go to Syria and
Anatolia, that's where we had the Mitani
Empire and the Hittite Empire. And the
Mitani Empire and the Hittites, their
rulers were of Arian or Indo-arian
origin. They were of Indian origin
essentially. when they had Indian or
Indo-arian names uh their rulers like
Tuarata and uh Paratwa and and so on you
know Sanskrit names essentially
and that is the time period we're
talking about is about from 1600 BC to
about let's say 1,00 or 900 BC that's
the time period we're talking about
that's when you had the Hittite and
Mitani empires in this region in
Anatolia and Syria
okay um and the oldest uh Sanskrit
inscriptions are found from this this
region surprisingly. Yeah. So this was
an out of India migration back in the
day right about let's say about 4,000
years before today must have started and
it's around 4,000 years before today
that we find the sudden appearance of
Indian uh zebu cattle in the region and
also in Egypt. So clearly there was a
migration of Indians out of India around
this time and this is definitely the
pre-Jewish period because the oldest
attested Jewish names and inscriptions
etc are from about 1100 BC or
thereabouts. So it is after the Mitani
and Hittite period. So
it makes sense that several kings,
numerous kings in this region, including
in present day Israel, right, would have
had Arian names, Indo-Aryan names
because yeah, they would have Indians
ruling Indian origin rulers ruling this
region. Uh very interesting revelation
and I shall check this out in detail uh
later on. But thank you very much for
this very interesting piece of
information. Thank you very much. I
really appreciate that. I will find the
PDF. I I'll find it. Thank you sir.
Anik says, "What is 12,000y old bugas
sphere which reacts to sunit?" I'm not
sure what that is. I've heard about some
bug sphere which is uh which has some
connections with UFOs and whatnot. Booga
sphere. Uh I'm not sure how old it is.
It is claimed it's so and so. So let's
quickly take a look at this bug sphere.
Booga sphere.
So, it's a mysterious seamless metallic
orb discovered in Buga, Colombia in
South America in March 2025 that's
generated global speculation regarding
its potentially extraterrestrial origin.
Uh, it reportedly exhibits or exhibited
anomalous behaviors including weight
increases, electromagnetic responses to
Sanskrit mantras and internal complex
fiber optic structures, its soccer
ball-sized metallic sphere. Uh it
apparently showed erratic
non-aircraft-like flight before falling.
Uh no visible welding in the object,
increasing weight. It increased from 4.5
lbs to 22 over 22 lbs. Apparently the
ability to cause nearby vegetation to
die and uh three layers of metal 18 18
microsphheres and so on and so forth. It
reportedly responds to 190 to 300 Hz
frequencies specifically to Sanskrit
mantras by vibr vibrating and emitting
electromagnetic surges. Uh some believe
it's an advanced alien sphere and some
suspect it's a hoax or a humanmade
object. Uh so that's what we know.
What's it look like? Let's take a look
at what this thing looks like. So this
is what the object looks like. It seems
to have some inscriptions in some kind
of heroglyphics or something or some
kind of ancient or or unknown uh script
possibly but we don't know what the
origins of this object are. So um it
doesn't say how old it is. I mean you
can't really date a metallic object.
Carbon dating is done only when it's
possible only when you have organic
material organic matter. And that's
where organic matter like like you know
human tissue etc or animal tissue or
plant tissue
that contains uh you know carbon and
there's a carbon isotope called carbon
14 that decays at a certain rate and
that's why we can date uh you know these
ancient artifacts if they contain
organic residue. But this metallic
sphere obviously won't have any organic
residue. So you can't do carbon dating
on it. So I'm not sure on what what
basis whatever dating has been assigned
to it if it has. So uh yeah so I don't
really know much about it. I haven't
studied this. I haven't uh looked into
the details. Uh is it real? Is it
authentic? Is it a hoax? Can't say for
sure.
Aniket says report says that Russia will
resume trade in USD. Okay, I'll keep an
eye on it. I'm I personally haven't seen
this thus far.
Uh okay, I'll keep an eye on this.
Anik says Dval said won't be bullied
will wait out Trump's term. Well, it's a
it's a reasonable approach to have. See
Trump's administration is well clearly
uh their policy is to bully everybody
including their allies including their
close allies and vasals including the
European nations their close allies
including everybody else and obviously u
they have this uh this policy towards
India that's of containment and bullying
and uh arm twisting and so on. So
obviously we would like to have a
productive and uh reasonably fair
relationship, mutually beneficial
relationship, friendly relationship with
the US, we would like to have that. The
US is the most important nation in the
world. We can't ignore it. So we would
like to have a good constructive
positive relationship with them. But as
long as their approach is such is that
of bullying and all that and arm
twisting and having maximalist demands
and uh demanding concessions and
demanding essentially vasage uh it
doesn't make sense to uh bend the knee
and cave in. So uh I haven't seen this
particular report of what Shidal said
but if he said that it obviously makes
sense right and uh I'm not sure if we if
the US approach will change after this
current administration um leaves office
the Trump administration but let's wait
and watch. Yeah because see
uh things change the world changes the
world evolves and uh as the world
evolves the approaches of various
nations evolve. So it makes sense to not
get bullied. Don't give in to armwisting
tactics. Don't give them everything they
want. Yeah. Uh don't give in to
maximalist demands and wait it out.
Makes sense. It is a reasonably it's a
not just reasonable it's a very good
approach to have.
Aniket says India is reducing oil
imports from Russia but the reduced oil
purchased by some unknown the reduced
oil purchased by some unknown country in
Asia. Yeah. So look, it doesn't really
make sense for India to give up
purchasing Russian oil. Russian oil is
discounted. That's number one. And
number two, we have a very good, very
strong and very important relationship
with Russia. It's our, you know, longest
close partner. longest is in the it's
the longest relationship in you know
with the nation that we have where the
nation is a close partner and it's a
pretty good relationship
and it's very important for India to
continue this relationship and to and to
take this relationship further and not
allow third parties to dis to to dictate
how this relation relationship goes with
Russia. Um
so the Americans are claiming okay Marco
Rubio is claiming in the US statements
if they whichever they put out they
claim that India has committed to uh
stop buying Russian oil.
Well that's what the Americans are
saying. India has not said any such
thing. No Indian statement has uh agreed
to what the Americans are saying.
So maybe it's this this this this may be
just one more American arm twisting
tactic where they claim that India has
committed to doing so and so even though
India may not have committed to doing
that and then by making this public
claim that India has committed that
committed this then they can exert
pressure on India to actually make this
happen. So uh India is obviously in a
difficult position.
Um we do want access to the US market.
It's important for India's exports
right? It's the biggest market in the
world. So we do need access to this
market but at what cost will we are we
willing to uh what cost are we willing
to pay to get to obtain access uh at 19%
tariff rate to this market? That's the
question. Um
so it's you know it's it's quite likely
that a lot of this oil that was being
purchased was coming through
intermediaries and third parties and
whatnot not directly from Russia. So
let's see how this goes. I I am hoping
that you know we don't just cave in and
stop purchasing Russian oil which you
know it sends messages to the world. It
sends a message to the BRICS nations. It
sends a message to the global south. It
sends a message to all of India's
partners that India will be bullied and
India will cave into arm twisting right
and that has a big effect on our
negotiations with other countries. So we
can't afford to let this happen. So
hopefully India will you know tough it
out.
Aniket says compare KR KP relationship
with inpk KR
KP what's KR KP
similar difference KR is Korea is it KP
is what
I'm not really sure
KR and KP India Pakistan I understand KR
Kyrgystan no Korea North Korea.
What What nation is KR?
Uh KR nation
nation abbreviation.
What's KR? South Korea, I suppose.
What's KP? What's KP?
KP. Nope. Nope. KP.
North Korea.
Okay. So you you asked me to compare the
relationship between
South Korea and India Pakistan and North
Korea and India Pakistan. Well, South
Korea you have to understand what what
is the nature of the nation. South Korea
is a US personal and their relationship
with India and Pakistan will be dictated
will be essentially dictated either
overtly or covertly by US interests.
Now South Korea has a reasonably good
relationship with India. I'm not sure
about its relationship with Pakistan.
Pakistan is an economic non- entity more
or less. Uh but I suppose they may have
some kind of relationship with with
Pakistan. With India we have a good good
relationship mutual trade and whatnot.
Ship building also I suppose to some
extent and other things as well. We
import South Korean products like
electronics and other things. Uh
Pakistan also would do that but does
Pakistan have a different kind of
relationship with South Korea? I'm not
sure. North Korea we have reasonable
relationship with North Korea. with
North Korea and Pakistan. It is alleged
that North Korean missile technology was
used for Pakistani for the Pakistani
nuclear military program etc. It's
possible. Yeah. Because see North Korea
is a Chinese asset Chinese and China and
Pakistan had this long diance which
still continues to to to a certain
extent. So so North Korea's relationship
with Pakistan will be mediated you could
say strongly affected strongly by China.
Yeah.
Bascar Bandit says, "Piety, sir, well,
Pyat to you. Hope you had a great
Mahashatri." Uh, yes. I hope everybody
had a great Mashivatri.
Uh, if no one will be arrested after the
Epstein files, assuming nothing happens
to powerful people, who benefits from
this? What long-term game is going on
here? Okay, let's assume hypothetically
that nobody's arrested, nobody's
prosecuted, everybody gets just gets off
scot-free.
Yeah.
And it looks like that's what's going to
happen. I mean, Bill Gates is very
clearly implicated in uh what's happened
in the Epstein files. Clearly implicated
and what's come out with respect to Bill
Gates is very damaging. Very damaging.
Even his wife, ex-wife has put out
statements about this, right, which kind
of kind of indirectly implicitly
corroborates
or doesn't deny the Epstein filed claims
about Bill Gates. And yet Bill Gates is
traveling the world. He's being hosted
in India. He's giving speeches in India.
He's visiting various states in India.
He's been given he's being given the red
carpet treatment. Right? So Bill Gates
looks like nothing's going to happen to
him. What about Howard Lutnik? Uh
Trump's minion, the Secretary of
Commerce. I suppose what what is his
designation? Howard Lutnik.
Howard
Lutnik. Secretary of Commerce. This
fellow, this fellow is all over the
Epstein files in the most disgusting
manner. And yet he is very much in
power. He has not been thrown out of the
cabinet by Donald Trump. Donald Trump,
what about him? So the point is it looks
like all these people who are high and
mighty, super powerful, super elite in
the US. Looks like so it's the super
wealthy and the super powerful and the
super connected looks like nothing's
going to happen to them. So the question
is who benefits from this? Why has this
disclosure or or huge number of files
why has it been disclosed? Lots of
redactions obviously the FBI and the US
government are protecting the accused
not the victims it looks like right who
benefits from all this uh in a lot of
cases you know various names have come
out Deepak Chopra has been exposed
Stephen Hawking apparently has been
exposed Elon Musk well his name does
figure but doesn't look like he visited
the island but not because he didn't
want to because Epstein didn't want him
to uh Bill Gates and so many of these
people so a lot of these people are
essentially
people who they are older people and
people whose
actions and activities and and relevance
was in the past they are no longer that
relevant today right so maybe it's it's
a way of retiring these people at least
even if no prosecution is done even if
nobody's thrown into jail their
credibility is gone now right Elon Musk
seems to be shielded to some extent uh
Bill Gates will continue whatever he
But he will no longer be in a position
of real power. He's in a position of
influence now perhaps. So it looks like
there's a big set of people who are
being retired, forcibly retired. You
people are now tainted, tarnished. Your
reputations are gone and it's a new
bunch of people who will now be in the
corridors of power, positions of power
and who will essentially wield the
levers of power and to some extent rule
the world. Looks like it is these newer
people who are the powerful people
behind the scenes in the US who benefit
from this long-term game. Take a whole
set of people who are very powerful,
very rich, very relevant in the past in
the 70s, 80s, 90s, 2000s, 2010s, and you
retire. You sunset them now.
Okay? And there's a new group of people,
the young people, those who in the in
their 30s, 40s, 50s,
okay? And those who are not mentioned in
the files who are now going to be the
movers and shakers and the wielders of
power who will now shape the future of
the world. That seems to be the
long-term game that's going on. that as
far as I see.
Pascar Bandit says uh how does a guy
like Mandani Mandani become mayor of New
York starts talking about socialist
policy is in the most capitalist city
and country on the globe rather how is
he allowed to do all this well Bamani
has won because the the
um
what is it what's the word I use
establishment
the establishment wants people like him.
Now, why would the establishment want
socialists
um to essentially rule over cities like
New York? So, New York is the financial
capital of the world, isn't it? It's the
most capitalist city in the world. The
US is the well the most capitalist
country in the world. And you have
people like Mamani and various others
Alexandria Okasio Cortez and Ilhan Omar
all these lefties socialists who are now
in increasingly in positions of power.
What is going on is the question. Why
are these people allowed to rise and
acquire what seems like positions of
power? How powerful are they actually
and what purpose do they serve? Maybe
the purpose they serve is to obfuscate
the truth. So just like
see the US president is not really the
person who rules the country of the U of
the United States. His the US
president's job is to divert attention
away from where the real power lies.
Right?
So it reminds me of Douglas Adams. Okay.
Douglas Adams, president of the galaxy.
Let's see what
did Douglas Adams say about the
institution
of the president of the galaxy.
Let's say
um
so the president of the institution of
the president of the galaxy is a cynical
absurdist joke designed specifically to
hide where real power lies. It's really
interesting, really precient.
So this is a science fiction book. It's
a it's it's a really funny science
fiction book and yet it is it's it's
still so relevant today. Yeah, it is
kind of you know in a sense a commentary
on on today's world. So according to the
guide, the president of the galaxy is
merely a figurehead with no real power
whatsoever. The actual job is not to
lead but to draw attention away from the
real power holders. Only six people in
the galaxy knew that the job of the
galaxy president was not to wield power
but to attract attention away from it.
Qualifications for the role. The
position does not require leadership
skills but rather a capacity for finely
judged outrage. It's designed to be a
controversial and infuriating role.
Anyone who is actually really capable of
getting themselves made president should
on no account be allowed to do the job.
Uh so he suggests that those who most
want to rule are by definition the least
suited to do it.
Um okay so that kind of does in a very
strange sense explain the institution of
the president of the United States where
the the objective the purpose of this of
the president is to draw attention away
from those who really have the power who
really wield the power. And similarly
when it comes to lower levels like
Mandani and mayors of cities and all
once again possibly the the purpose of
these people is to draw attention away
from where the real power lies.
And if you want to know
well where the real power lies or maybe
lay in the past in a city like New York
City read this book called the power
broker
by Robert Caro. this
it's a massive book okay it's it's a
massive book huge book not an easy read
but if you want to understand how power
really works well check this book out so
I think it's possible that the object
the the purpose of having people like
Mamani and whoever else these these
lefties these socialists who who who
have values that are essentially counter
to the American values. The purpose of
having these to the purpose of elevating
these people to various positions of
power is to hide to obfiscate where the
real power lies. That is most likely the
the purpose and objective of allowing
such people to rise to these so-called
seats of power.
Nikit says why are some people upset
about India's 0% and US US's 18% tariffs
which are less than our competitors when
tariffs are paid by Americans not us uh
continued
there's a continuation somewhere let me
see where is the continuation anit
I'm trying to see if Anik has asked a
continuation I don't see I don't see
that okay so the question essentially is
which is kind of self-contained why are
some people upset about India's 0% uh
and US's 18% tariffs when tariffs are
paid by Americans, not us. Well, it's
because of of misreporting,
misinformation and so on. It's true that
India will be paying 18% tariffs on no
India won't be paying the US will be
imposing 18% tariffs on a variety of
goods that flow out of India and enter
the US. Indian exports to the US. Now
when it comes to other nations, the
tariffs are much higher that the
Americans have imposed. Um let's see.
Okay.
What tariffs what
tariffs has
has the US imposed on the uh top 10
economies?
Let's see. Um what tariffs has the US
imposed on the Okay. Is there is the I
mean
one second let me just uh
let's try it again
okay top 10 economies
it won't tell you tariffs in the second
Trump administration let's see it's
going to be a gigantic article
okay uh on
India China Um, France,
uh, UK, Germany,
Italy. Let's see. Once again, it's not
telling us. I'm not going to an old
article.
Okay. Do we have something here?
US tariffs by country. Reject all. Thank
you. Um, Australia 10%, reciprocal
tariffs. Bangladesh 37%, Brazil 10%,
Cambodia 49%, Canada 25%. China 34%, EU
20%, India 26. It's 26.
Uh, India is 19 now. This seems to be
outdated. Okay, that's February 1,
Indonesia 32. So, India is 19, EU,
European Union is 20, Indonesia is 32,
Israel is 17. Okay, that's a special
nation. Japan 24%, Mexico 25%. China
34%, 20, Canada 25%,
uh Pakistan 29, South Korea 25,
Switzerland 31, Taiwan 32, Thailand 36,
UK 10, US, UK is a special Vietnam 46%
and so on. As you can see, as you can
see, India has got one of the lowest
tariff rates, one of the lowest tariff
rates. Right now if you expect that we
would have we should have absolute
reciprocity that India should also
impose 18% tariffs on American goods but
it's not going to happen. It's not going
to be an equal relationship. The US is
it's not an equal of India. India is no
equal to the US. Right? So if you look
at it relative to the tariffs the US has
appi imposed on other countries
including its allies you will see that
India has got a great deal. But people
won't see this right? People will just
listen to some YouTuber somewhere or the
other or some news reader somewhere or
they'll just see whatever is there on
social media and whatever people are
outraging about and based on that based
on several various headlines and things
they'll they'll form an opinion and
they'll get upset about it. It takes
time to analyze things right I mean even
if it takes a few seconds actually but
still even that is too hard for most
people to do and that's why people will
just do this outraging.
Basker Bandit says, "We know aliens and
UFOs only visit the US." Oh yes. Oh yes.
They only visit the US and they
allegedly are distractions for the
public. But how exactly is the American
public made to be distracted by such
things? What is the process of this
disinformation?
Well, the process of this disinformation
is various podcasts, various books, uh
news reports, social media reports and
so on. you all you have to do to create
a certain uh to to to to create and
maintain and maintain a certain
narrative is to feed the public constant
bits and bites and pieces of information
from various channels distribution
channels. That's all it takes.
So social media is is a great medium for
this whether it is uh X, Twitter or
Instagram or Facebook or whatever you
know various videos and reports of UFO
activities. they will various UFO
believers uh who will do podcasts
uh then news reports. So by by
constantly drip feeding
such you know pieces of information at a
certain rate you can keep the public
engaged in in these matters right and uh
if you want the public to have a surge
of interest in UFOs and aliens then you
suddenly increase the rate at which this
information is fed to the public. So
like uh
late 2024 there was this huge surge of
UFO sightings in the US, right? New
Jersey, you had like hundreds of UFO
sightings every night. You you still I'm
sure if you look at uh X, you can still
find uh I'm sure you'll be still able to
find videos from late 2024
from New Jersey and other parts of the
US where you have all these UFO
sightings. So if you want there to be
this upsurge in interest, all you have
to do is is is increase the tempo at
which this these pieces of information
are released to the public. And that
that's that's the process of this
disinformation.
So what do I believe about UFOs and
aliens? Look, as far as aliens are
concerned,
aliens, alien life in the universe,
non-human life outside of planet Earth,
I'm pretty sure it must exist. The
universe is just too vast. How many
stars do we have in the universe? maybe
10 raised to 23 which is one followed by
23 zeros. That's how many planets we
that's how many stars we most likely
have in the universe roughly. Roughly
give or take. Okay.
And assuming each star has just one
planet. Well, we have 10 to 23 planets.
If one out of a billion are capable of
harboring life, then that's 10 to 17
such planets. If one out of a billion of
those life harboring planets are capable
of intelligent life, that's 10 to 11
planets with intelligent life,
intelligent life. So you have what
100 billion potentially planets in the
universe with potentially intelligent
life just, you know, by plugging in
those those
very approximate numbers. So, I'm pretty
sure there's life out there, but the
universe is so vast and it's so empty
that it's it's impossible almost
impossible for us to possibly ever find
out, ever detect the signature of life.
So, so that's where I stand when when it
comes to life in the universe. I'm
pretty sure it exists, even intelligent
life. But have we encountered it? I am
very skeptical, extremely skeptical. I
haven't seen any hard evidence. So,
that's where I stand with respect to
this.
Baskar Bandit says immigration in Japan
people are not happy. The leader Madame
Sai Takichi says they will take care of
it. Uh surely this can't be just bad
policies. Now since they are vasads of
the US have the masters decided to
change their demography. Well of late in
the past couple of years the the the
nation of Japan has been allowing all
kinds of immigrants to come in. bunch of
Bangladeshies, a bunch of people from
god knows what other countries and the
Japanese people are very very upset with
that. Pakistanis, Bangladeshies who are
carrying out religious process
processions on the streets of Japan, the
kind of things that people in the UK are
familiar with, they have started doing
that. Uh they have been demanding land
for cemeteries, for bur burials,
Japanese land for that and so on. So uh
the people are very upset with this. The
people the people of Japan are are are
very concerned about their culture.
Um and they they are very
anti-immigration.
Japan as a society is very
anti-immigration and we've got to
respect that
every society should decide its own
policies.
Every nation should have the absolute
sovereign undeniable right to decide its
own policies. And if a nation decides
that they don't want immigrants, well
good.
It's their right. Who are we to judge
them for that?
So the people aren't happy. Clearly the
people aren't happy and now it looks
like these policies will be reversed.
Now you are right to say that Japan is a
US vasal. No question about it. So
since you had this happening the past
few years. It looks like the US had
decided that Japan will now become this
nation that will accept immigration. It
looked like that. The Americans seem to
have decided. Now, Madame Sana Takichi
is against that and looks like she will
implement policies that will end
immigration.
So, does this bring her into conflict
with the US or has the US agreed to
this? That remains to be seen.
Japan obviously does face a massive
demographic crisis. Their birth rates
have plummeted horribly. The population
is aging rapidly
and it's it's a major crisis for Japan.
It's an existential crisis for Japan. So
the US will say, "Oh, the solution is
immigration. Bring in people from other
countries." But then Japan is no longer
Japan. Eventually Japan loses its own
cultural and civilizational identity.
Right? So uh what does Japan do about
this is the big question. I think uh
I think ending immigration
makes sense, but how will that produce
more children? It's not that easy. I
mean look at the structure of the
society. It's very hard for people to to
take care of kids and so on. So it's
it's a big challenge for them but looks
like this new government is going to
shut the doors on immigration. Uh will
this bring them into conflict with the
US? That remains to be seen. So let's
wait and watch. As of now I don't have
an answer to that question. Whether the
Americans have agreed to this or not
because these decisions happen behind
closed doors. They never never spoken
about in public. So let's wait and
watch. Ritik P says why is the US
ambassador Sergio Gore visiting India's
western command?
I don't know.
Right. If we if we look at this Sergio
Gore
Gore,
uh where's this Twitter account? I'm not
a robot, sir.
Traffic lights. Okay, let's find some
traffic lights and buses. Okay, let's
find some buses. This proves that we are
human, right? Now, we will decide, oh
yeah, this fellow is human. So Sergio
Gore, let's go to his Twitter account.
Dark mode enabled. And now we have
bright mode. Sergio Gore. So let's see
what he has been tweeting about. Just
landed in Chandigad. Looking forward to
visiting the western command of the
Indian army.
Right. So clearly the US ambassador
is visiting the western command of the
Indian army.
Why is it doing this? Well, from his
perspective, he would like to visit
every command of the Indian army and
find out exactly what's what the Indian
army is up to. He would like to visit
the Indian Air Force commands, Indian
Air Force bases, Indian naval bases. He
would like to visit Indian submarines.
He would like to visit Indian nuclear
reactors and nuclear facilities. He
would like to visit everything. The
question is why are we allowing the US
ambassador to visit
the Indian army's western command? Why
is the Indian government allowing the US
ambassador to visit
the Indian army's western command? That
is perplexing actually,
right?
It's perplexing. I don't have an answer
to this. It's perplexing and concerning
in my opinion. I am concerned. This
raises questions in my mind that I will
not air right now that I will not
speak right now. But it raises question
concerns in my mind. So I am not sure
why the government of India is opening
the doors of the Indian army's western
command to the US ambassador.
Are we so friendly in with the US now?
I mean which other countries do we give
s this sort of access to? Why the US? I
I don't have an answer. It's it's
concerning.
Basar Bandit says did we have the
concept of psychologists or therapists
in ancient Bat as we have in the as we
have in the present day West where two
or more people sit and talk or listen or
did this entire concept originate in the
west itself?
It's a very interesting question. But do
I have the answer to this?
I don't have the answer to this because
we don't have the records of uh the
past.
We have some texts that that have
survived the the Turk destruction of
India and the British destruction of
India. We have some texts that survive
like the Sushut Sam and so on. A few
texts about India's medical practices
and so on. But the majority of our
ancient texts were destroyed with the in
the destruction and burning of our of
our great libraries in the great
universities of India. Right? So if we
had the concept of psycho psych
psychologists and therapists etc it
would have been recorded in those texts
millions of texts but those texts are
lost.
So as of today we can't say I don't know
if we had this concept. I mean our our
society was very advanced. Our
civilization was very advanced people
where everyone specialized in something
that was the the basis of the Jati
system, right? Everybody was part of a
lineage that was based in a certain
occupation and everybody specialized. So
children would initially get basic
education in temples, you know, basic
stuff like language, grammar,
arithmetic, basic history and so on. And
then they would be educated by their own
by their own families or clans or or
jatis specialized uh professional
education.
So I'm sure we would have people who may
have been engaged in uh the profession
of of psychology perhaps that would have
been potentially a jati
but uh you know the records are gone so
we can only speculate as of today.
So as of today when it comes to
psychology it looks we have to say it
originates in the west and I'm sure we
must have had these things but can't say
for sure because we don't have the
records anymore.
Hanish Sharma says sir since you don't
look abused enough I'm guessing you
haven't watched tumb yet. I haven't
watched it yet. I I haven't watched it.
I do
I'm I'm grateful that you keep reminding
me I still haven't watched it. Uh I'll
try and find time for it in this coming
week. Tumb it's not a very long movie,
right? About one and a half hours, two
hours maybe. I'll try and watch it.
Thank you for the reminder, sir. Thank
you.
Basket Bandit says, "Sir, why military
powers have their eyes on Antarctica?
It's all ice today. Maybe it was
different before." Yeah, it was
different before. What's the
geostrategic significance? Also, the
story is about Operation High Jump.
Okay, what is Operation High Jump? I'm
not sure. Uh, sounds vaguely familiar,
but yeah, Operation
High Jump.
High jump. What is that?
Um,
US Navy Antarctic Developments Program
1946 to 47. What was it? What was
special about it? Deployed 4,000 over
4,000 men in 13 naval ships to test the
ability of military operations in the
polar environment. Established a
functional base at Little America 4 and
learned some of these shortcomings of
heavy groundbased equipment on snow and
ice. Okay. So, it's some kind of
military expedition in Antarctica,
short-lived, 4748, that sort of thing.
Um, yeah. So, I haven't studied
Operation Him, so that's all I can say.
Now, why do
most major powers have their eyes on
Antarctica? Obviously, it's all eyes
today. I mean, if you look at the, you
know, if you go to the map, you will see
that it won't the maps won't even show
you the features, you know, the
geographical features on Antarctica.
Here's the map. We go straight south
from India. Here we have Antarctica. If
we look at uh satellite images, well,
it's just it's all just white. It'll
show you some features in some part of
the the continent
as you can see a little bit here, but
the rest of it is just white and maybe
it's deliberately blanked out.
some coastal regions you can see some
features some terrain features even
not a lot right I mean if I look zoom in
here
I don't think it's showing me actual
images is it looks like it's showing
some kind of images but you never know
uh so the thing is the deal with
Antarctica is that it's a massive
continent you know the south pole is
located in Antarctica it's massive
And there was a time when Antarctica was
green, okay? A long long long time ago.
Uh there was a time when it was green
and it was not located all the way down
south where it is today. There used to
be this superc continent called Pangia
and Antarctica was very much part of
that and there were there were forests
and animals and whatnot on Antarctica
back in the day like millions of years
ago.
So what's the deal with Antarctica?
What's the strategic geostrategic
significance? First of all, Antarctica
most likely has a lot of natural
resources.
Um, oil and gas, various minerals,
uh, possibly metal, iron, ore, and maybe
other things, maybe maybe boxite. So,
various kinds of natural resources are
found in Antarctica. I'm sure the
Americans and others have have done some
some digging, some searching, some some
research, and I'm pretty sure Antarctica
is is is rich in natural res resources.
So, that's one significance. The other
significance is that it's it's an empty
continent and uh whoever controls that
controls one more chunk of the world.
Uh obviously it's very hard to live
there. The temperatures are
frighteningly cold like minus god knows
what minus 50 perhaps maybe below below
that as well. So it's it's very cold of
course
but if you have technology I mean you
can definitely have bases there and have
people survive there. India also has a
couple of research stations there on
Antarctica. So what's the significance?
The significance is that it is rich in
natural resources and it's empty
territory that that obviously is is you
know it's lucrative
for for any major power.
Han Sharma says what killed Bob Wulmer
was it his upcoming book about spot
fixing? Was it Jamaat or simply he knew
too much about Pakistani fixing scandal?
Bob Vulmer was this uh cricketer, wasn't
he? English cricketer who was the coach
of the Pakistan cricket team.
Um
was it the coach of Sri Lanka? No, that
was Davmore, wasn't he? Okay. So Bob
Woomer was a former cricketer who was
the coach of the Pakistan cricket team
and he was found dead under very strange
suspicious circumstances.
I think in 1999 was it
right after Pakistan lost a match to
Bangladesh.
That's what I recall about about him. I
think he was a left-handed batsman and
something. Let's let's try and Oops.
What is that? Give me a second. Let's
try and find out details about Bob
Woomer.
So,
what's up with the search? Search is
lagging.
Okay. 2007, not 99, 2007.
So,
uh English cricket coach, cricketer,
commentator.
Okay. the the 2007 World Cup in the West
Indies.
Oh, the all the Pakistanis lost to
Ireland, not Bangladesh. They lost to
Ireland and he died a few hours after
that. And he played cricket for whom?
Playing career. He played cricket for
England.
Okay.
Yeah. Okay. So, he was a allrounder.
Okay. And he died in 2007.
and uh the circumstances of his death
seem to be suspicious, but maybe it's
kind of been brushed under the under the
carpet perhaps. I'm not sure. Uh
Peter Robuk also died under circum
strange circumstances.
That's another suspicious and strange
death in cricket. Peter Robuk who was
an English county cricketer and then he
moved to Australia. He was a phenomenal
writer, cricket journalist and then yeah
so the question Hanish Sharma is asking
is what killed Bob Woomer
not sure see the Pakistanis lost to
Ireland which is so strange Pakistan has
this strange habit of losing to losing
unexpectedly to teams that they would
typically not lose to. So in 2007
Pakistan was a pretty strong team. See
today's Pakistan it's not a great team
right? I mean they regularly lose to
India and they are no longer a top team
but back in the day Pakistan were one of
the top teams in the world when you had
people like Wasimi Makram Vakarunas
Imran Khan in Zamam Javeid Mandad and so
on top it was a top team there was a
time when India could not defeat
Pakistan in world cups we always did but
otherwise India could not defeat
Pakistan India was like that and today
it's the other way around so but
Pakistan obviously has this great
tradition you know this glorious
tradition of match fixing and
You know Sal Malik has been banned for
banned for life for match fixing. Wasim
Makram was implicated but it looks like
he has been able to escape that. So Sali
Malik was definitely implicated. A
number of Indians were also implicated.
Yeah. So we'll not discuss that here.
And uh who's that guy? Muhammad Amir was
found guilty of spot fixing his bowling
no balls like 3 m ahead of the of the of
the crease and of the of the line. that
sort of thing. So Pakistan has has this
great uh tradition of match fixing, spot
fixing, whatever. And it's possible the
Pakistanis were doing that in the 2007
World Cup as well. And the speculation
is that maybe Bob Wulmer discovered some
of this and was was about to reveal that
disclose what he had discovered and
maybe that's why he was taken care of.
So it's all speculation. the official I
don't know what the official narrative
is but it looks like it's not no longer
under investigation Bob Wulmer's death
but it was very strange that he would
just die like that. Yeah. Basar Bandit
says Shri Kingish Teujin Khan's empire
was five times larger than Alexander the
Barbarian. But why Mongolia did not
industrialize or accumulate wealth
within Mongolia? Today geopolitically
they are not big.
Um, why did Mongolia not industrialize
and not accumulate wealth within
Mongolia?
That's a great question. Looks like
Chingishan's philosophy was not that of
extraction like what you see with the
western colonial powers in the past 500
years. So even when India would expand,
for example, let's take just one data
point which is the Chola conquest of
Shiv Vijaya of Indonesia. So about 1,000
years before today roughly Rajendra
Chula decided to go and invade Indonesia
right Shiv Vijaya the the Shiva Empire
and he crosses the the Bay of Bengal the
the the
Kalinga Mahasagar he goes all the way to
Indonesia conquers Indonesia
and vasalizes the whole of Indonesia but
he did not go and extract anything out
of Indonesia he did not plunder
Indonesia and take take away their
wealth and enslave them and extract
their resources.
Right? No such thing.
That did not happen.
So what Rajendra did was simply
effective regime change and come back
home. He did not extract any wealth. He
did not plunder the place. Similarly,
Chingis Khan was not did not have a
policy of extraction and plunder. His
policy was that of well because of
various reasons eventually what ended up
is that he ended up doing was expanding
his empire significantly hugely right
and whatnot uh karakai
uh karaz China and so much more so uh he
expanded his empire but he did not
extract any wealth out of the places he
conquered
so I think it's a cultural thing that
you know you don't steal
So, so that's why you will see that
Mongolia never accumulated wealth.
Uh, I suppose Changistan believed that
his wealth was his people. Yeah, pretty
idealistic way of looking at things. But
yeah, Mongolia never extracted wealth.
Why did Mongolia not industrialize?
Well, I suppose Mongolia never saw the
need to industrialize. The Mongols were
simple people. They still are, right?
They their their entire philosophy,
their entire lifestyle was nomadic and
they did not see the need to create big
industries and extract things out
resources out of the bowels of the earth
and create mega cities and mega
industries and whatn not
right
they never saw the need to do that
they said let's let's you know live in
an orderly fashion so if my empire has
China it this karaz and the Chinese way
of life is different from the quarasian
way of life which is different from
other parts other other parts of the
empire let them all have their way of
life but I will interconnect everything
and create one system for my entire
empire but I want extract wealth I want
plunder I want industrialized there's no
need for that everyone's living happily
peacefully everyone's happy as they are
everyone's wealthy as they are nobody
desires accumulation of wealth so let's
not do that right so it's a it's a it's
It's a philosophical thing. It's a
cultural thing. It's a civilizational
thing. The eastern cultures never were
such that they would they wanted to
hoard all the wealth of the world in one
place, extract everything out of other
places and hoard all all wealth for
themselves. It was never that way. And
that's why Chingishan did not do that.
Pascar Bandit says, "How absurd or naive
it is is it to think that $1 will be
equal to three Indian rupees by 2029."
I am not sure who would imagine that
this will happen.
Look, anything is possible but what's
the mechanism by which this happens. So
has somebody given
this sort of deadline or this sort of
has some somebody made this sort of
prediction that $1 will be equal to
three Indian rupees by 2029
and by what mechanism have they proposed
that this will happen? Um
I don't know. Uh I think it's a really
far-fetched thing. If it happens, I'll
be very pleased.
But will it be great for India? Will it
be bad for India? There's a lot of
factors that go into these things,
right? If the Indian rupee appreciates
in value,
then it's a problem for uh
it's it's a problem for exporters, isn't
it?
So yeah, you know, I'm not sure if if
you want to become an export oriented
economy for example, then I don't think
it's great for the Indian rupee to
appreciate significantly.
So yeah, I don't know. There are all
kinds of people who make all kinds of
you know such claims.
Yeah, you decide whether you whether you
believe or not.
Uh Hanisha says, "Ishan Kishan take a
ball. What an innings. What are my
thoughts?" Well, outstanding innings.
Ishan Kishan was out of the Indian team
for a while, wasn't he? For for some
reasons. I don't know. The BCC had kept
him out of Indian cricket for a while.
Was it disciplinary reasons? Was it some
other reasons? I'm not sure. But he's
back and it seems to be in the form of
his life. Clearly, Ishan Shankishan. And
maybe the break has done some good to
him. Maybe it's it's, you know, given
him more hunger, the more of a desire to
prove himself and to, you know, prove
his doubters wrong. And that's that's a
great fuel for an athlete.
the desire to prove everyone wrong.
Those who who wrote who wrote you off.
So clearly he seems to be in tremendous
touch right now. Tremendous form and uh
he should keep going. His innings
yesterday was I I've seen the
highlights. It was pretty powerp packed.
He should have gone on actually to at
least triple figures but okay not bad.
So overall great great innings.
Harisha says, "You talked about why
India should not allow dual citizenship,
but I really couldn't understand it.
Would you be kind enough to explain to
us one more time maybe with an example?"
Sorry, no issues. No issues. So, uh
why should India not allow dual
citizenship? H
So let's say so let's understand what
citizenship means. If you're a citizen,
you can you have certain privileges that
a non-citizen doesn't have. You have the
right to vote. You have the right to
prop to to acquire property. You have
the right to own the majority share of a
company. Uh you have all kinds of
privileges as a citizen that
non-citizens don't have.
You may, if you're a citizen, you can
even become prime minister. You can even
become a minister, cabinet minister.
you can become the head of the RBI
right so
we've had Raguram Rajan was a US citizen
right when he was the head of the RBI
I'm not sure how that works but okay so
there's a lot of privileges that
citizens have that non-citizens don't
have now let's say India allows dual
citizenship India US
that means that technically a US citizen
can potentially become in the prime
minister of India technically hypothe
Hypothetically it's possible is that
good for India's national interest that
a person who is India's prime minister
holds foreign citizenship
which means who has at least 50%
allegiance to a foreign nation is that
good for your national interest and
understand this when it comes to the
India US relationship it's not a
symmetric relationship it's an
asymmetric relationship there's a
massive power asymmetric country. The US
is about 20 to 25 times more powerful
than India.
So if you are a citizen of both
countries simultaneously,
the US can ensure that you have way more
allegiance to them than to India. They
can engineer that through a variety of
means.
Right? So if if that is the situation
that India allows dual citizenship that
let's say the US then the US is a past
master at playing certain games they can
engineer the rise of certain people
within India who are dual citizens and
who will then take over power in India
and by doing that the US can remote
control the future the fate of India is
that a good idea I'm just taking the
example of the US it could be some other
nation too So why does the US allow
this? Because the US is the most
powerful nation in the world.
And whenever they have citizens who are
dual citizens, they will ensure that
the cards are stacked in such a manner
that these dual citizens can't do any
harm to the US and they typically will
have more allegiance to the US except
for maybe one or two countries which we
will not discuss here. Okay. So, so
these are some of the issues right with
dual citizenship. The US
will ensure that nobody can uh can harm
their interests but India we are more
compromised. So we have to be more
careful.
Bhaskar Bandit says how to be like
Abijit Chad Chava in real life. Thank
you sir for all you do endless gratitude
and support. You inspire us and make all
of us to be better every day. Love you
and Jay Paradam. Thank you so much for
your very kind words. How to be like me
in real life. Well, I would say why do
you have to be like me? Be yourself. Be
the best version of yourself.
Um,
that's what I would say. Everyone's
different. Everyone's unique. Be the
best version of yourself. Understand who
you truly are. Take the time to
understand yourself. Understand
your true nature, your true
characteristics. Understand why you were
put on this planet. What was the purpose
of your existence? Right? Most of us as
we go along, we kind of forget who we
are and why we are here. Most of us
never figure out why why we are here.
What is the purpose of this specific
lifetime? This specific life that we
have and who actually are are we? Most
of most human beings don't even ever in
their entire life truly figure out who
they really are. So I would say
figure out who you are. Figure out your
purpose in life and and try and be the
strive to be the best version of
yourself. That's what I would say. Don't
try to emulate other people. And if you
want to emulate, well, find out what is
it that you admire in a certain person
because in every person in every person
has a combination of good traits and not
so good traits, strengths and
weaknesses.
So I would say make a list of the top
five people you admire or maybe top 10
persons you admire in the world and make
a list of the characteristics and traits
of each of those people that you admire
that will tell you what is it that you
are drawn to attracted to and what you
really value in human beings and then
try to inculcate those traits in
yourself that's what I would say
right so that is my actual advice to you
don't try to emulate one person
completely
Um, how to be like me in real life, I
don't know. I just be myself. All I do
is try to be who I am. Um, I do have to
improve a lot in a in a variety of ways.
So, yeah, be yourself. That's what I
would say. All the best and thank you so
much, sir.
Agam Senpai says, "I just came back from
South Korea. In reality, most people
look very pale, lighter than southern
Europeans who look more yellow olive
golden. Why called yellow?
Um,
so the Asiatic race, right, is it's
called the yellow race or something. I
don't know why Eastern Asian people are
called yellow in the west. It's one of
those old racial stereotypes from the
19th century, I suppose, 18th or 19th
century.
Uh, maybe these see even even if you
look at the native Americans, they are
called red Indians.
I mean, if you look at Native Americans,
they are not red, they're brown, right?
Native Americans in the US, in North
America or in South America or Central
America, they're brown. Native Americans
in the far north of the of North America
are typically paler skinned and when
they are exposed to the sun, they their
skin becomes reddish. So maybe that's
why the plains Indians or whatever, they
were called red Indians, but they are
actually brown people. They're not white
or they aren't red. Similarly, when it
comes to various Eastern Asian people,
the the Koreans are pretty pale skinned.
The Japanese are also pretty pale
skinned. The Chinese, well, they their
skin tone varies
and not exactly white. Uh,
but some other tone, I would say. Is
that what they call yellow? I'm not sure
what why it's called yellow. Look, I've
never seen a yellow person in my life.
Okay. Only the Simpsons look yellow.
The cartoon series, you know. I haven't
seen a yellow person in my entire life.
They Oh my god, this person is yellow.
I've never seen the person who looks
like that. So, I have no idea why the
why the why the Europeans called the
Asian Eastern Asian people yellow. U I
suppose it's one of those racist
stereotypes.
Mac 4 Janu says, "Your view on Chinese
education? Any lessons for us?
Chinese education is brilliant. China
probably has the best education system
in the world today." probably right and
if you want to know my views on Chinese
education once again I will direct you
to my old live streams in which I have
discussed this in detail so let me find
that find that and I will I will give
you the pointers so if you go to my
channel okay my channel is on the screen
right now if you go to the live tab uh
right now episode 331 is live but let's
go to the oldest okay and uh this is old
episodes and if you go to episode 28,
30 and 31
that's where I discuss education and I
think it's in episode 30 that I
discussed the Chinese education system
and
and and and all the strides they have
taken and how they have systematically
step by step reformed their education
system. It's it's I mean you really have
to appreciate what what China has
achieved with their education system.
Tremendous
tremendous work they've done. They
probably have the best education system
in the world today. And in 1980 they
have one of the worst systems in the
world.
Yeah. Probably the Indian education
system was better than than the Chinese
system around 1988 maybe in 19 1985. But
from the 19 late 1980s onwards the
Chinese started systematically
reforming their education system step by
step by step.
So let's say it's 86 86 to 96 2006 2016
that's 40 years. In 40 years they've
taken one of the worst education systems
in the world and transformed it into the
best education system. Step by step
they've gone step by step in doing that.
And there are so many things they've
done to to make this happen. So I can't
explain all of that to you right now
over here. It'll take a long time to
explain. Check out that those those
three episodes especially episode 30 in
which I have explained in detail.
So lessons for us. Yes.
Yes. A lot of lessons for us. Watch
those episodes you will know.
Rishi Barot says how are almost all
Chinese Communist Party leaders aligned
towards their national interest and not
corrupted by power? Has there been a
case otherwise? Thank you.
Are all Chinese Communist Party leaders
aligned with their national interest?
See, one of the factors you have in
China, the Chinese Communist Party is
that it is permanently in power. Okay?
There's no democracy there. There's no
um you know, the the country is is not
hostage to votes.
And the Chinese Communist Party decides
the long-term future of China. They have
this five year plans, 10 year plans,
five year plans. and they know what
direction they want the country to go
in. They have a vision for China in
2049. They have a vision for China where
China needs to be by 2100.
And because the Chinese Communist Party
is permanently in power, they can work
towards that long term. In India, we
have this 5year election cycle where
every 5 years you don't know what's
going to happen to the country. If the
government changes, if the people vote
in a new government, policies can take a
U-turn,
right? and everything that was done in
the past can be completely undone in a
few months.
So in the Chinese Communist Party, it's
not like that. Now the Chinese Communist
Party
has this social contract with the people
of China. The contract is that we will
rule over you as dictators
and you will allow this because we will
give you the best living standards in
the world. We will improve your living
standards and we will make make China a
great country. So we will give you this
and in return you will allow us to keep
ruling as dictators. That's the social
contract the Chinese Communist Party has
with the people of China. So for this to
happen,
every action has to be aligned with the
national interest. Otherwise, you lo you
break the social contract.
And obviously there's some there's been,
you know, corruption in China and there
have been high-ranking leaders who have
been executed for for corruption. There
are people who are jailed for
corruption. Corruption in any society,
you're going to have some corruption.
But in China at least there's a
egregious corruption is is punished very
harshly and non- egregious corruption is
perhaps tolerated to a certain extent as
long as it does not come in the way of
the national interest.
So what kind of corruption may you have
in China?
Let's say you are let's say you are a
person wealthy person who wants to set
up um a new new industry.
Okay. and the process is taking time. So
maybe you put some money below the table
and the process gets
gets gets shortened. So maybe
hypothetical example maybe it would have
if if the approvals may have taken 2
months maybe they'll now take 5 days or
maybe 2 days. So that actually helps the
Chinese national interest you see. So
that sort of corruption is is tolerated.
And when it comes to corruption by
corrupt being corrupted by power well
I'm sure every leader has this you know
every leader depending on the on the
person and their their their
psychological profile. Everybody will be
affected by power in some way or the
other but you know there there's the
system of checks and balances in China
which ensures that no leader becomes too
big and if a leader gets too becomes too
big they they are you know they're taken
care of. know it's a pretty complex
system. It's a very very um competitive
system. The political system in China is
a dog eats dog world. Only the toughest
and the most capable rise to the very
top. So the system is such that the
right people rise to the top otherwise
they'll be eaten up somewhere on the
way. So that's how China is and that's
why China is able to do things that well
India lags behind it very badly.
Rohan bidi says origins of Russia India
Russia friendly relationship
India and Russia well
India and Russia have had relations for
centuries actually
um so the the origin of Russia the
origins of Russia are go back about a
thousand years with the Kievan Roose
people okay um the first capital of the
RS people was Kiev which is now the
capital of Ukraine Ukraina
and then I'm giving you a very fast
speedrun of history here and then uh for
a couple of hundred years Russia was
under the Mongol yoke for a couple of
hundred years Russia was ruled by the
Mongols. Then the Mongols eventually
became weaker as every empire does and
Russia became free again. And then
instead of having the capital in Kiev,
you had the rise of the duchi of Moscow
and Moscow became the new center of
power. And then you had various kings
and rulers and eventually Sars, right?
And during these times you had Indian
merchants who would go and and trade
with with Central Asia and Russia.
So for centuries Indians were trading
with the Roose people, Indian traders,
Central Asia etc. You even find there's
this uh you know there was this Lakshmi
statue or Vishnu statue that was found
in Russia. Let's let's uh let's look
into that right um Vishnu statue Russia.
So where was it discovered? Why is
search so slow? Why is it lagging today?
Anyhow, an ancient Vishnu idol estimated
to date to the 7th or 10th centuries AD
was discovered in the Tara Maya village
of Russia's Walular region.
So, u WGA region.
So, this is what the the the Morty looks
like.
So, we had so my my point is there were
this ancient ties between Russia and
India mainly trading ties and all. had
Indian priests who uh Indian Indian
merchants who would go and trade with
Russia who would live in Russia. Um they
would do their Hindu rituals of bathing
in rivers and all in the Bulgar river
the freezing vulgar river and all that.
So we have these ancient ties with
Russia and then in the 20th century
after the after the transfer of power in
Shir Neoji was very friendly with
Russia. He was very impressed with
Russian uh socialism. So he ensure he he
he
went ahead and uh engineered developed
strong relations with Russia
and that's kind of the origin or the
continuation of the India Russia
relationship
uh and that continued even after the the
sad demise of Shin Aruji.
Rahul Mishra Rahul Mishra has no
question but thank you very much sir.
Thank you very much indeed.
Rahul Vishra says, "Can you tell more
about the Bor Stone shrine, please?"
Bagor stone shrine. I am not aware of
this. Let's let's Google it together. I
am not aware of this. Bore
stone shrine. What is this?
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
The Bagor one paleolithic shrine
located in the Son Valley of Madhya
Pradesh uh dates back to about 9,000 to
8,000 BC which is about 11,000 years
before today. Excavated in 1982 circular
platform with the centy place triangular
stone uh continue concentric
laminations.
It's a shrine of a goddess.
Um okay. The central stone is naturally
formed rectangular triangular piece of
sandstone with concentric reddish brown
and yellowish red laminations.
Uh early evidence of shaki worship. The
stone is a yantra.
Uh right. All right. So let's what's it
look like? Let's see.
So bghur stone.
Okay. Okay.
So this is uh apparently how it was
discovered.
One of the oldest uh evidences of shism,
shaky worship, goddess worship. That's
yeah, I just read it out. I I have heard
of it, but I have neverh had the time to
look into it. That's what I can tell
you. So that tells you, my friends,
that's what this this is another example
that tells you how ancient our
civilization is.
If it's 9, if it's from 9,000 BC, that's
11,000 years before today. The oldest
Saraspati Synindhindu archaeological
site is Birana in Hana which dates back
to about 7,500 BC which is about 9 and a
half thousand years before today. Then
you have another archaeological site in
Ladak which is about 11,000 years old.
Then you have the Bagor stone shrine
temple which is also about 11,000 years
old. The more we look into our ancient
past archaeologically, the older we're
going to find that our civilization gets
because of new evidence that emerges. So
it tells you and this is an example of
goddess worship, Shaki worship, right?
People still worship Shy today.
11,000 years we've been doing that.
Yeah. So that tells you how ancient our
civilization is.
Adi Brahdan says alternative education
in India current education is dumb.
Current education is rotten. It is it is
rotten to the core. Yeah. The current
education system. What about alternative
education in India?
Um well one thing people could do is can
do is uh homeschooling right? Um
don't send your kids to schools. Have
them schooled at home. Maybe parents can
do it themselves if they have the time
or they can uh hire tutors who can do it
if the tutors are good. And then you
know you have these uh
there are these boards right open
schooling boards
10th standard 12th in national institute
of open schooling and all that you can
do. So you can get your 10th and 12th00
degrees even if the kids are
homeschooled right. Um and you can use
whatever curriculum or syllabus you want
for homeschooling and you can inculcate
the right ideals um the ability to think
critically the right knowledge the right
information the right thought patterns
the right analytical patterns in kids
you know scientific thinking uh thinking
from first principles all of that and so
that's definitely possible apart from
that there is the gurugul system that
some some places you know in some places
some parts of India we have gurugals
revival of gurugals that also is another
option
So we have some options like that but
the at the end of the day you still need
degrees because without degrees you will
not get a job. So whatever happens at
the end of the day you still need these
pieces of paper which means you have to
somehow reinsert yourself into the
education system and get those damn
degrees and then go through the grind of
getting into the job market and becoming
another corporate drone. I suppose
Ranir Ratur says what was the Vagna coup
2023 any strains between Russia and
China? The Vagna coup. Well, I have
discussed that live. The Vagna coup.
The Vagner coup, right?
Uh
there there is see during first of all
let me see my old live streams where I
may have discussed the vagna. Give me a
second.
Uh once again let's go to my panel.
Okay.
And uh Okay. Let's discuss. Let's see
where we can discover the vagna.
So, there's a lot of history here. I've
done more than 300 live streams, but
we're going to have to go further down,
further down, further down. Further
down.
Okay, give me a second.
So many live streams I've done, haven't
I?
So, do we have something with Vagna?
Vagnner
I'm I I'm sure I did live streams around
that time when the Vagna Wagner incident
happened.
When was the first live stream after the
uh Russia Ukraine war? It was 97 98
around that.
Um yeah 91 no 89 was when the Ukraine
invasion started and then eventually 23
we had the Vagna. So the the question
you're asking is what was this Vagna
right? Um
what was his name? The guy who died in
the plane crash
what was his name?
Um definitely not pregoin
uh
Wagner group former leader
Yini
uh
let's see yeahghini precaution right
precaution he died in a plane crash in
August 2023 and he led this uh this coup
attempted coup in uh 2023 so the coup
was he entered it was about the
an attempt to perhaps take over Moscow
or something right so let's see how it
happened if I recall correctly so the
Vagna group was obviously uh involved in
fighting in Ukraine right and they they
re-entered Russia around Rosto on dawn
and then made a move on Vosco on on on
Moscow. They went north towards Moscow
and somewhere along the way they were
stopped
and eventually um later on Yavghini
Pojian died in a plane crash. That is
what happened. Now the details obviously
you can look up that's what it was. It
was an attempt by Yini Pojin
to
maybe oust Putin. Didn't work out
obviously. Pratip Kumar Roy says about
Bal statue burning in Iran. There was
also a pillar Ashwarath which they
burned. She was the wife of Bal. I
researched the internet and found out
about Anat Bal's sister and others. The
thing about this name Bal. Bal means
Bal meant Lord
in in the which Sumerian or Mesopotamian
language whichever language it was. So
it's not like Bal is one god. There were
multiple gods who all had the title of
Bal like Lord, Lord Shiva, Lord Ganesh,
Lord Dish, Vishnu, Lord Brahma, Lord,
Lord, Lord. Right? In English, in
English we say Lord.
So Bal means Lord or Master. And there
were multiple gods with the title of Bal
like Bal Hammon, Bal something else,
Bal Malok I suppose. So if you look
here, Bal
Hammon,
Bal Hammon was the supreme deity of the
ancient Carthaginian religion.
And uh
then you have another Bal uh
Hadad.
Bal Hadad was a west symitic deity of
storms, thunder, rain, fertility etc.
Bal. Uh so once again this is another
god with the title of Bal.
Now the the Bal statue burning in Iran
probably is one of probably Hammon.
But this is a Carthaginian god, right?
Not
what about Bal Malok
Malok and Balakanite blah blah blah blah
blah. Malik Malik king Bett.
So, it's it's kind of hazy. It's kind of
murky. I
can't tell you for sure which Bal is
which. But when it comes to the
vilification of Bal in the Hebrew Bible,
one of the Bal gods is mentioned as a
god that demands child sacrifice.
And there was this place near Jerusalem,
near Shalain
back in the past where you had
this group of people, this this culture
where they allegedly passed young
children through fire to make their bal
god happy. And this bal god was called
Moolok.
Now who was Mo is a big question. Maybe
molloc is an entity and
we mollocit or or or a code word given
to a god who doesn't who they don't want
to name perhaps. Is maloc actually
Yahweh? Is Malok some other god? We're
not sure. So Bal is not one god. Bal are
there are multiple bal gods and many of
the bal gods it looks like there was
child sacrifice offered to them.
uh and
the wife of Bal there was a pillar which
the word Ashira Anat
okay what is Asher let's find out
who was Asher
um
Asher was a major ancient west somatic
mother goddess uh consort to the supreme
god L also called Bal in Kananite
Phoenician etc etc etc
Ashira. And who is Anat?
Anat
prominent northwest Semitic goddess of
war, hunting, fertility, etc., etc.
Sister to the storm god Bal.
Okay. Why does she wear Assari? I
wonder.
Okay. So, um,
right. So, that's what I can tell you
about Bal.
When they say Bal, they sometimes mean
one of the Bal gods. Which one? I'm not
100% sure. Um, and I heard about this
news of the burning of a statue of one
of the Bal gods in Iran. Yeah. All
right.
Amisha says, "Have you heard of Jack the
Ripper, the serial killer?" Very famous
or rather infamous, very notorious
serial killer in 19th century London.
Right.
18 what? 1880s, 1890s.
around that time and which part of
London I forget the name of that part of
London today apparently it's dominated
by Bangladeshies so the that that area
of London where this this serial killer
operated
today that area of London is is
populated by mostly Bangladeshies
apparently
uh let's look it up shall we so first of
all Jack the Ripper right and and his
identity has never been actually uh
confirmed Jack
the Ripper.
White Chapel. White Chapel. So 1888,
that's when he did this murders. He u he
he murdered some uh some uh women
apparently prostitutes or something. And
White Chapel district. So today it's
it's full of Bangladeshes. Apparently
56% of White Chapel residents identify
as Asian. I suppose they would all be
majority Bangladeshes. It has yeah all
that but going back to this guy
so he he has never been identified.
There have been various uh suspects that
have been presented but the the identity
of the of the serial killer Jack the
Ripper has never been identified for
sure. There are some people who were
prime suspects uh when it comes to the
London police but nobody was arrested,
nobody was uh prosecuted. Nobody was
punished for this and even today it's
kind of an open
open area of research and uh people are
still kind of obsessed with Jaktar even
today.
Pratip Kumar Roy says so these were the
original pagan gods of Israel. Now I
somewhat understand the fight between
this and the Abrahamics spearheaded by
Freemasons.
The ancient original pagan gods of
Israel. So Judaism
was originally a polytheistic religion
and later Yahweh became the primary and
on eventually the sole god the only god
of the Israelites. So let's let's see
this uh uh Judaism
uh polytheistic
originally.
Let's see. Was Judaism originally
polytheistic? Yeah. So Judaism or
protojudaism evolved from polytheistic
canonite roots? The canonites. Yes.
Transitioning through monolith to strict
monotheism over centuries. Originally
Yahweh was part of a pantheon headed by
El
alongside other deities like Asharak and
Bal and eventually became exclusively
worshiped around around the Babylonian
exile. So so Judaism originally or the
roots of Judaism were polytheistic but
eventually Yahweh became the only god.
Uh yeah so you had pre-Abrahamic gods in
Israel, multiple gods, gods, goddesses
and all of that and then Yahweh becomes
the soul soul god.
dur once once uh Judaism becomes
monotheistic
and yeah I'm not sure about the
Freemasons I've never really studied the
Freemasons what their agenda is what
their purpose is
and what connections they may or may not
have with Judaism or or Abrahamic
religions I'm not really sure about that
Rohan says why did Janism never grow as
much as Buddhism
see why did Buddhism become such a big
phenomenon is the big question right
over
Why did Buddhism bodh the dharma become
such a big big big phenomenon?
It was an obscure fringe path of dharma.
Here are all these dharmic paths right
every all all kinds of uh spiritual
leaders, philosophical leaders,
philosophers etc. who had various
conceptions of what the universe is like
and they had their own um own
philosophies which were part of the
dharmic umbrella. So many of these came
and went. Many of these are probably
lost. So Buddhism was one of these both
the dharma. Goautam Buddha was a
religious leader who was uh active in
north in northern eastern India sarnath
and so on.
And during his lifetime Buddhism was not
a big thing.
It was pretty obscure.
And then Emperor Ashoke for political
reasons makes Buddhism mainstream.
So before Emperor Ashoke makes Buddhism
mainstream, nobody in the subcontinent
knew about both the Dharma. Nobody knew
about this. And then because of imperial
patronage, Buddhism explodes in
popularity.
And that's why that's how it suddenly
goes all over the all over the
subcontinent and eventually beyond the
subcontinent. See for any religion to
thrive
or any religious path to thrive you need
funding you need patronage
you need a champion. And when the
emperor himself is the champion
well the path is free for you. Right? So
it is Ashoke
who artificially
transformed Buddhism from a from an
obscure dharmic path into a global
phenomenon.
He did this for political reasons.
Ashoke now for when it comes to Janism
Jina Dharma they never Ja never had the
sort of imperial patronage. Of course
you have uh one of the descendants of
Ashok who was it
who built lots and lots of Jane
monasteries. Okay let's let's see okay
Ashoka
Ashoka the great let's see his
descendants let's let me tell you one of
his descendants maybe great-grandson or
something
um
Mahendra
Kunal
Kunal was blinded wasn't he? Uh D is the
father successor Srati. Srati. Yeah.
Srati Moria the grandson of Ashoke.
He according to Jane tradition he built
150,000 Jane das and made 15 million
Jane Mortis idols. He had taken an oath
to dig the new foundation of a new janal
every day and that sort of thing. This
is what Wikipedia says. As always, as
always, statutory warning, Wikipedia is
not necessarily a reliable source of
information. I just use it for you know
so that because it's quick but don't
always rely on Wikipedia. Be very
careful with it. The point is we had
Srati Moria who was uh who was a big
patron of of uh Janism right um and
Ashok was a great patron of Buddhism but
Srati wasn't as powerful and as
influential as as Ashok.
So you had times in India where
journalism was a big deal in South India
you know for a time in Karnataka etc
journalism was a very big deal. So these
waves ups and downs come and go.
VS says if Epstein files caused so much
controversy and havoc I wonder what
would happen if they release all the JFK
files. What's your take on this?
They won't release all the JFK files.
Um yeah, if they release the JFK files
and we truly find out what happened, it
will be a massive massive massive
controversy and even today it will be
very controversial and it will possibly
show various US institutions in in a
certain light that they don't want to be
seen in. Right?
See, it's very clear that what
they the official narrative about the
JFK assassination is false. It's a lie.
There is the Warren Commission report,
right? Warrant Commission. Let's see.
Warren Commission.
The Warren Commission. Come on. Why is
Google lagging?
The Warren Commission investigated the
assassination of President JFK. It
concluded that Lee Harvey Oswald acted
alone
and Jack Ruby acted alone.
Okay. Okay. The warrant commission. Uh
so according to the warrant commission,
okay, uh what's his name? Lee Harvey
Oswald.
The guy who said I'm a pati. That guy,
he acted alone. He was on top of a big
build of a tall building, maybe 10th,
11th or whatever floor. He had one rifle
with him, a single rifle with a scope
and he shot JFK from behind.
That's what the Warren Commission says
that Lee Harvey Oswald shot JFK from
behind. Means the bullet came from
behind his head. It hit him behind on
the in the back of the skull. If you
watch the Zapruder
video,
which is the video in which JFK is shown
to be assassinated, you can see that the
killing shot comes from the front. His
head is snapped back like that. his head
is snapped backwards, not front. If the
bullet hits from the back, the head will
be snapped forwards because a bullet
cont
has a tremendous amount of velocity and
momentum and it's going to snap a
person's head forward or backward
depending on what side of the head it
it's from. So, it's very clear that John
F. Kennedy's head head snaps backward
like that. So the killing shot came from
the front, the one that blew his head
up. And yet the Warren Commission says
that there was only one guy who shot the
guy, the president, and the killing shot
came from behind, which is obviously
such an obvious lie. So if the JFK files
are released, it's going to cause a
political earthquake in the US. Yeah,
the US still won't be able to take it
even now, decades later.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "I recently found
out about the blood curling oaths of the
Freemasons. Also, there is a Freemason
symbol in my engineering degree
certificate." All right. What is the
Freemason symbol? Let's shall we find
out? Um,
Freemason symbol,
it's some ge geometrical thing, right?
Ruler and something like that.
Freemason symbol. Okay. Okay. The square
encompasses, right?
Square and compasses.
Um, this thing here.
Okay. Uh, I am not aware of the blood
curdling oaths of the Freemasons because
I have not studied their history and
their whatever. So, I don't know about
that. But, uh, if you have Freemason
symbol in your engineering degree
certificate, it may or may not be a
coincidence. Maybe it's a coincidence
because those are square and ruler. It's
kind of square and compass. It's kind of
something that you associate with
engineering anyway, right? Maybe it's
just a coincidence.
Uh Jagjit Bida says gold and silver
history and future value replaceable.
See, gold and silver have historically
been stores of value. Why is gold
a store of value? Why is silver a store
of value? Gold is a a reliable store of
value because gold is rare. It's a rare
element.
You don't have tons of gold lying around
on the planet, right? There's only a
finite amount of gold that can be
extracted from our planet and it's very
rare. So that's why gold has
gold gold is that's why a historically
reliable store of value. Even silver is
a metal. It's pretty rare. It's more
commonly available than gold. I mean
back in the day people used to have
silver plates and silver cutlery in
India. It was very common. But still
silver is still a precious metal. And
there was a time when the Indian
currency was back backed by silver not
by gold. But historically gold is the
real uh store of of value when it comes
to uh monetary wealth.
So uh that's in brief the history of
gold. The reason why it's so valuable is
because it's so rare. Um, and you can't
produce gold out of thin air. You can
print paper notes, paper currency out of
thin air. You can print it. Paper can be
printed, paper currency, but you can't
print gold, right? That's why gold is so
much in demand. That's why people buy
gold. So gold is a reliable store of of
value. Is gold replaceable? It's not
replaceable. Unless we can go and start
mining asteroids and and bring millions
of tons of gold back to Earth. In that
case, the value of gold will go down.
It'll devalue, right? But that that's
not going to happen anytime soon, at
least the next century or two, right?
Because mining an asteroid is it's
obviously it doesn't break the laws of
physics. possible, but it's a
monumental, almost impossible task
because you're going to have to go and
look at lots of asteroids and discover
gold somewhere and then mine that and
bring it back to Earth. Very, very
difficult. Almost impossible with today.
Today's technology impossible. So, gold
is not replaceable. Neither is silver
actually. But gold obviously is more
valuable. Even copper is becoming
valuable actually now. Yeah.
Golden Bird says, "What if pharma
companies are act are already spying on
North Sentinel Island with biometric
drones, animals, and collecting human
waste for their research?" Well, what if
I am not aware of any such thing.
Um, it is the government of India's
responsibility to ensure no such thing
happens. Uh, North Centelland Island is,
you could say, a protectorate of India.
It is part of Indian territory. It is
part of um India
but the way we have positioned it is as
a protectorate of India. So we have
essentially given it de facto
sovereignty. The people of North
Sentinel Island have their own culture,
their own language, their own way of
life and the government of India has
decided we will not interfere in their
affairs.
We will not impose Indian laws, Indian
constitution, Indian reservations etc.
on the people of North Central Island,
Indian um judiciary, Indian police,
Indian whatever. Let them live their
life the way they have been living for
tens of thousands of years and we will
ensure that nobody interferes in their
internal affairs. So we are going to
protect them and we will not interfere
which means that if we have decided upon
this then we have to protect these
people and ensure that nobody is able to
interfere in any way.
No pharma company, no no no no other
nation, no travelers, no vloggers, no
YouTubers, nobody should be allowed to
go there, right? Um, so it's the
government of India's responsibility.
That's all I can say.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, I recently
started watching videos about this
Chinese professor Jang YouTube channel,
Predictive History. Very interesting
channel. All right, sir. Thank you for
that recommendation.
I shall check it out. Jang
Adish
Adish Readish Hir says, "Was the Axis
defeat inevitable once the US entered
the war or could different strategic
decisions have changed the outcome?"
Okay.
um
could different strategic decisions have
changed the outcome. So the outcome is
the outcome that we got is that the the
uh the allies led by the US won and the
axis which was mainly uh Nazi Germany,
Imperial Japan and fascist Italy those
three together they lost. That was the
deal that was the outcome. Um so was
this defeat inevitable once the US
entered the war
or could Germany, Japan, Italy etc. have
done something that could have u changed
the outcome.
I think
I think the access defeat was not
inevitable once the US entered the war.
It was the decisions and choices of of
the of of Nazi Germany of Adolf Hitler
that led to the defeat of Nazi Germany.
See, one of these strategic
choices they made was to abandon
the the attacks on Britain and focus on
the USSR. So they made a choice. Okay,
let's So they had this blitz creek going
on, the blitz on London and the UK and
the UK was was under siege. It was under
siege.
If they had continued that and taken the
UK, which they possibly were capable of,
then the whole of Europe was under their
dominion.
And if they had then not attacked the
USSR
but consolidated their gains and stopped
it over there then it was very difficult
for the US alone
without the UK's help to you know
turn the tide. That's one thing. So one
ch one really bad choice was abandoning
the attack on the UK and turning
attention to the USSR.
They had this pact with the USSR, right?
the Nazis, the Molotov Ribbons fact and
they broke it eventually.
So then they turned their attention uh
on the USSR. They launched operation
Barbarosa
and there also instead of going straight
for Moscow and effecting a proper regime
change and taking out Stalin, the Nazis
decided to go south to the Caucasus
because there was a lot of oil and gas
there. Aaranbaku or that that region,
right? Kokas region, lots of oil and
made made sense from a strategic from
from a certain perspective that you want
access to the energy there. But what
about Stalin? What about the the Soviet
regime, right? So if they had focused on
straight away going after Moscow and
defeating Stalin right away, they could
possibly have done that. Yeah. So these
choices changed the outcome of the war.
So if they had not made those choices,
if they if they had first gone for the
UK and taken it, then the U US would
have found it really really difficult to
defeat Nazi Germany.
White user says US helps Pakistan and
also funds it with which it launches
terror attacks on us. But I don't see
Indians boycotting and hating the US. We
only boycott countries far smaller than
us. Don't you think it's hypocrisy?
Say the US is is a special nation. It's
the most desirable nation in the world
for individuals. Every everybody wants
to go and settle down in the US, right?
What do most Indians want for the
children? Study hard beta. Get a great
degree. Then I'll take a big loan of 1
cr or whatever from the bank. I'll say
send you to the US to study there. Study
very hard. Get your degree. Get a job
there. Get a H1B visa. eventually get a
green card, settle down, become a
citizen and that's the path
right so when you have this aspiration
for the U with with respect to the US
why would you hate the US
right and most people aren't aware of
the fact that the Pakistani terrorism is
funded and financed by the US so today
Pakistan is not able to launch terror
attacks on India mostly but from the
1980s all the way to the 2000s
All the Pakistani terrorism was
essentially funded and financed by the
US. But Indians don't realize that most
Indians don't realize this
and even if they do then they kind of
turn a blind eye to that because US best
country in the world number one country
right is it hypocrisy maybe it's
hypocrisy call it whatever it is.
Pratep Kumar Roy says Sar previously you
said there are only four sovereign
nations in the world later you added
Israel to the list. Why do you think
Israel should be on the list? Yes, I had
not thought it through properly.
If you are
a person with a functioning brain, then
you will keep on evaluating the way you
see the world and sometimes you'll find
that you made an obition somewhere. So
you correct that and if you have said
something in public, you said you
correct that in public. There's nothing
wrong with saying that you know what I
missed something in the past. Earlier I
said there were only four. Today I have
realized no no I made a mistake one more
nation exists that should be on the
list. So that is called correction. So
yes I initially said the four there are
only four sovereign nations the US,
Russia, China and India. Then I realized
let me think properly. Oh no no no no
Israel is also independent and
completely sovereign. So yes then I made
this amendment this change that yeah
it's actually five sovereign nations is
why do I think Israel should be on the
list?
Why do I think Israel is a completely
sovereign nation? Because it is. It is.
It's it's the one nation that has a
genuinely special relationship with the
US and it has unconditional US support
no matter what happens. When you have
the unconditional support of the most
powerful nation in the world in a way
that the most powerful nation in the
world does not interfere in your
internal affairs, then you are not just
sovereign, you are super sovereign.
Yeah.
So,
so
Panduranga says Vijayagar Empire
significance and downfall.
Vijayagar Empire significance and
downfall. I am not an expert on the
history of the Vijayagar Empire. But I
will give you a recommendation.
Let me give you a recommendation. Okay?
If you want to know the history, learn
the history of the Vijayagar Empire in
brief. Uh let us go to YouTube.
Adijit Chavda
Chavda Sepalak
Krishna
and uh not these two but um
no no now no journey into Vijay Nagar.
So this is a 48 it's it's a 50 it's
almost a 60-minute video
that in which I had a discussion with
sep and in which sepalak krishna has
explained in brief the history of the
vijayagar empire. Okay. So yeah watch
this video and in that that video will
give you uh the information that you
seek. All right.
Uh Bat SF says what about medical mafia
destroying health of Indians and its
cronies like liver do destroying our
faith in traditional systems like
Ayurveda and Siddha. Uh I am not
you know an expert on these matters. I
don't know about this. I I know this
this guy called Liveroc on Twitter and
it appears that he's controversial in
some way. I have not interacted with
him. I have not checked out his timeline
in any great detail. So I am not aware
of uh what his stand is. He is he
destroying our faith in traditional
systems like Ayurved za. There are some
people who have this crusade right this
crusade of attacking everything that is
traditional in India attacking it
through rationality and modern science
and whatnot. So there there are these
people who have this agenda this this
this crusade that they are on. I use the
crusade word
you know consciously.
So there is that but I am not aware of
this guy. I I'm not aware of what his
actual you know agenda is. Now medical
mafia destroying the health of Indians.
I once again I am not an expert on these
matters. I have not studied this. I've
not looked into this in detail. What I
can tell you indeed in in the high level
is that u India's medical system is is
is a business.
Healthcare has become a business in
India just like education. Education is
a business. It's where people can make
huge amounts of money and healthcare is
a business.
So if someone is sick, that person is is
a valuable resource to the medical
industry because you can extract money
out of that person.
So it's it should not be like that. I've
said this in the past and it's it's kind
of controversial but my opinion is that
in a civilized society
the government should extract taxes from
the people. Yes,
but in return the government should give
the people free totally free healthcare
and totally free education
as it used to be in India when India
used to be civilized.
So take taxes from the people. Sure.
Make the people pay taxes but give them
free healthare healthare and free
education. That's what a civilized
society is like. We are not no longer a
proper civilized society unfortunately.
I mean if you turn health care and
education into businesses then you are
ruining the future of the of your of
your civilization.
So yeah, Pratib Kumar Roy says, "I
discovered recently about early
Freemasons had all the knowledge about
architecture, engineering, science.
After European renaissance, they were
responsible for the scientific
developments in Europe. Sir, are you
Freemason?" I am the last person who
will be a Freemason. I am I I will
categorically state this. I am not a
Freemason.
Okay? I am not a Freemason. I will never
be a Freemason.
I don't even know who the Freemasons are
and uh what their agenda is, what their
origins are. I haven't studied them so I
can't say. But yeah, it's an interesting
group of people. So yeah, I am not a
free nation. Come on.
Abishek Singh says Indo-China battle of
Rzangla 1962 120 versus 3000.
the battle of Rzangla.
I will
invite you all to visit Ladak if you can
and if you visit Ladak I'll tell you
where to go. Okay. Uh where's our map?
Here is map. We go to Ladak.
So the capital the largest city in Ladak
is Lei. When you go eastwards from Lei
you will reach Pangong. So the Pangong
lake. Now you have places like uh
Spangamik. Spangmik is a village. Man is
a village. Mira and you can stay in this
villages on the banks of the of the
lake, great lake. But go further and
visit Tushul.
Okay, visit Chushul.
Chushul is is a essentially a village,
small town.
And if you go further, you will reach
the Razangla war memorial
over here.
And if you visit this place, they will
show you a movie, a a short movie of
about 15 20 minutes in which they will
show you all the details of this battle,
the battle of Rjangla in which 120 or so
Indian soldiers fought against 3,000
Chinese
nearby in this region. Okay, somewhere
here. Rzang lies right over here
somewhere.
And yeah, so you this Razangla war
memorial is right it's just a few
hundred meters away from the battle
battlefield actually
and if you go further go back what you
will find is that there is this border
meeting point you will not be allowed to
go there is this border meeting point
and you have this Chinese uh
installation here and then you will see
this this Chinese road
So this is Chinese occupied territory.
This is Chinese military infrastructure
and you can see the Chinese when you are
going back to you know going back to
Tushul or whatever from the Zangla war
memorial. So uh I would highly highly
recommend people those of you who have
free time and who want to see more of
India to go to Ladak and visit uh the
Rzangla war memorial
and find out what actually happened from
the Indian army themselves. The Rangla
war memorial is an army installation. So
when you go there you you have to enter
your details, your name, your address,
your phone number and so on and then
you'll be given a tour by actual army
personnel.
It's a great experience. Go for I I
would I will highly recommend everyone
to to go and have this experience.
Sam the gamer says how to stay calm like
MS Dhoni. Well, I suppose MS Dhoni is
the right person to answer that
question, right? I can't answer on his
behalf, but how to stay calm? Well,
develop a calm mindset and uh be be
prepared. You can be you can stay calm
in all situations if you are prepared
for the situations. If you've done your
practice and you know how to deal with
everything, then you can stay calm. If
you haven't prepared well enough and you
don't know how to deal with very
situations, then it is hard for you to
stay calm. So, MS Dhoni was always well
prepared, wasn't he? Right? Tremendous
amount of practice and fitness and all
that. So, he's prepared. He knows how to
deal with things. That's why I suppose
he was very calm. One of the reasons why
he was very calm. Okay. Pratep Kumar Roy
says, "Did you see the film The True Man
Show 1998? Hollywood is so much more
than Bollywood. We are far behind
everything from the west, Asia and
everyone." I haven't seen The True Man
True. Jim Carrey, right? Uh Jim Carrey
and he lives in this fake makebelieve
universe and um yeah, he's being uh
every action of his life is being
recorded and broadcast to the world.
That sort of thing. Uh I haven't seen
it. There's so many movies that I have
missed. I'm sure it's it's a great
movie. Yeah.
Um Kit Gupta says, "Howdy, sir. How how
to you? Uh can you please help me
understand the Nagorno Karabak and
Kosovo conflicts respectively?" Well,
that's two massive conflicts and that
will take a lot of time to explain both.
But how about we discuss one of these
conflicts, the Nagoro Karabak or Artasak
conflict, right? So let's go to the map
and we shall discuss the Naguro Karabak
conflict
in detail uh in brief in detail detail
it will take hours to understand okay
I'll tell you in brief so when we're
talking about the Naguro Karabak
conflict we're talking about
uh a conflict between Armenia and
Azarbaian okay so when the USSR
disintegrated in 1990 1991 all these
Republics
like Turkmanistan, Usbakistan, Georgia,
Armenia, Azarbaijan, Kazakhstan,
Kyrgystan and so on so forth. All these
became independent. They declared
independence.
So Armenia and Azarbaijan also declared
independence. Now when they were part of
the USSR, they were all you could say de
facto Russians. They all spoke Russian.
Russian was the main language and so on.
But once they became Armenian Azabajan
again their old ethnic rivalry came back
to the four and
and there were regions there is this
region called Artasak okay it's also
called Nagoro Karabak
Artasak it's now called Artasak Ajar by
John
so it's this region you'll the map won't
define it it's over here which is
claimed by both countries so in 1991
when Armenia was stronger and they they
they took over Artasak after after a
brief war essentially
and later Azarbaijan by the 2020s had
become more powerful. They had the
support of Turkey, they had the support
of Israel and then they went to war with
Armenia and then they took over Artasak
most of Artasak.
So Arthasak the the term that was used
in the 1990s was Nagoro Karabak. Today
it's called Arthasaka and uh it's it's a
pretty old and very nasty rivalry that
these two nations have. It's an ethnic
rivalry. The Azarbaijanis are Turic in
uh by by culture and religion and
language. Armenians are Armenians. So
the Azarbaijanis have support from
Turkey and also Israel. Why does Israel
support Azarbaijan? Because Israel buys
Azarbaijani oil energy. So it needs to
support Azarbaijan. For that practical
reason they support Azarbaijan. Turkey
supports Azarbaijan because Azarbaijan
is a Turk nation. Okay. And Turkey wants
to create a pan to run corridor all the
way from Turkey all the way to the Turk
nations like all the way to Kyrgystan,
Turkmanistan, Usbakistan, Kyrgystan,
Kazakhstan, Turk nations. So the
inconvenience over here geographically
is Azarbai is is Armenia and Turkey
wants to wipe Armenia out of the map of
the world
and that's the whole thing. So that in
brief is the Nagoro Carabah conflict.
Okay. This region that both countries
claim. See historically you go back 200
years, 300 years, all of this was
Armenia. There was no place called
Azarbaijan.
It was all Armenia. It was all the
kingdom of Armenia. Armenia is a very
ancient kingdom that's that dates back
more than 2,000 years. It's one of the
first Christian countries in Asia. Okay.
And before Christianity, it was
Indo-arian,
Indo-Iranian, probably Zoroastrian. And
before Zoroastrianism, well, you know
what? So that's this that's the story.
So the conflict is about territory. And
now uh Azarbaijan has the upper hand.
Sam the Gamer says, "Next science
episode. What are rogue planets? You
would you like a science episode? If I
do a science episode, the viewership
will be like 1/4 of what it is right
now." But I I'll be happy to do it. What
are rogue planets? What are rogue
planets?
I don't know what a rogue planet is.
Does the term rogue planet exist?
Is it a planet that that has broken free
of the gravitational influence of a of a
star? Is it that rogue planets? Let's
see.
Uh
rogue planet
free floating. Yeah. Okay. So, okay. I
was not aware the this term is being
used right now. Rogue planets. So, free
floating planets, planets that have
broken free, like I said, of the
gravitational influence of their host
star. So, in a in a solar system in a
stellar system, you have a star at the
center and you have a bunch of planets
that go around the star because of the
stars massive gravitational influence.
Now, when it comes to all these planets,
there are planets of different sizes.
And these are in different orbits.
Sometimes the orbital interactions are
chaotic. It's a multi-body system. It's
an endbody system. And sometimes the the
planetary interactions because of the
influence of the planetary of the
gravity of each of the planets.
Sometimes it causes a planet to be flung
out of the orbit and out of the solar
system. Somehow a planet may get enough
escape velocity to escape the
gravitational pole of its own star and
then this planet goes free floating in
the universe. Right? So it is no longer
attached to a host star. It's just out
in space in in interstellar space. And
apparently these are now called rogue
planets. So very hard to detect them but
they can be detected through various
means. Maybe through gravitational
lensing, through microl lensing perhaps.
There is gravitational lensing which
through which you can detect black holes
and very massive objects. Dark matter
can also be detected through
gravitational lensing. But when it comes
to smaller objects like maybe rogue
planets or small black holes, you have
to use microlensing. Well, through
microlensing, I suppose you can detect
rogue planets.
Um I don't read cerillic so
so I won't be able to read the name but
okay. India is the second largest beef
exporter
and as cattle once stop producing milk
they are sold to butchers. That raises
question on being vegetarian who consume
milk but cares about animals. What's
your take? Don't drink milk to save cow.
H that is um well
so is India the second largest exporter
of beef? First of all, let's see this
uh largest beef exporting
nations nations.
Okay, let's see.
Give it a second.
Brazil, Australia, the US, and India are
the world's top beef exporting nations.
Brazil is number one. Australia, India
is a major global supplier particularly
for buffalo meat. So buffalo meat is
also I suppose called beef. Yeah. The
top three countries by volume are
Brazil, Australia and India.
Would you believe it? India is a major
beef exporter. And let's say it's
buffalo meat. Still buffalo is almost a
cow, right? It's the same face. Color is
different.
What's my take on this?
H what's my take on that's a very
difficult question right there right
our culture
you don't kill cows right so how has
India ended up becoming a major beef
exporting country even if let's say 80%
is buffalo meat why is 20% cow meat
so the question you're raising is what
you're saying is that once a cow stops
producing milk that cow is sold to
butchers
Because otherwise you going to keep
feeding the cow until the cow dies and
that's a drain on your well on your
wealth from a financial standpoint.
Yeah. Okay.
Um
so the question is let's say you're
vegetarian you consume milk. Of course
if you're vegetarian in India you
consume milk but you care about animals.
So should you stop
drinking milk to save the cow?
I don't know.
Most people won't be able to stop
drinking milk, right? Indians love milk
a lot and most Indians won't be aware of
the fact that you know um this issue
that that milk cows once once they're
old they are sold to butchers.
Um I'm not sure what the solution is.
Should people stop drinking milk?
But for vegetarians milk is a major
source of protein. Otherwise vegetarians
will be like what what protein do they
have? Pulses. Yeah, milk is a major
source of protein for them. I I don't
know. I don't I don't think there's an
easy answer anywhere here. I think the
government of India has to take a stand
about this. I mean on the one hand, it
may be a major booster for our GDP.
Yeah, I think the government has to take
a stand on this. Of course, our culture
says you you don't kill cows. So why is
India
a major beef exporter? I don't have an
answer here. I don't have an answer. If
I was the person taking making the
decisions, I would ban it. But I'm not
the person making the decisions.
Dangra says profang
var
Judah
subi ra Jerusalem key or Israel may
Nvidia investment barat may roch child
YouTube does not let me see did not let
me see this in send this in English okay
professor jang pravishar so first of all
my Hindi I know how to read and write
Hindi but my reading speed is very poor.
Why is it very poor? Because I spent a
bunch of time in outside of India as a
kid. Okay. So once I came back I had to
I had to learn Hindi as if I was a
foreigner and I never developed that
speed in reading and writing especially
in reading in Hindi but of course I can
read. So, professor Jang pervar pax
judika ra jerusalem or is nvidia
investment ro I I'm not aware of this
professor jang I've not seen professor
jang somebody else recommended him
professor jang just now a while ago few
minutes ago an hour or so ago so I'll
check out professor jang in his channel
I have not seen that now pax judika I'm
not aware of what he has said about pax
judika sabir uh sabir jerusalem key or
so Does Professor Jang speak about tax
Juda and all roads lead to Jerusalem?
Israel
uh Nvidia investments in Israel. So I I
don't know. I'm not aware of this. Um
but I will check it out. Maybe next time
I'll have an answer for you. Right now I
don't know. Barat Moschields really ros
are investing in India. Really?
Obviously they won't do it directly
indirectly. It's somehow I suppose I
don't know. I've not seen I'm not aware
of it. But uh thank you for the the the
pointer. I will pick out Professor Jang.
The second time someone's recommending
Professor Jang in today's live stream.
So I'll check it out. Lassia has become
a new YouTube member of this channel.
Thank you very much Lassia. Welcome to
the membership of the channel and I am
very grateful. Thank you sir. Oh ma'am
thank you.
Rrook Nual says is Pakistan changing? I
hear voices against radicalism. I think
it's changing in Pakistan. Are you
hearing voices where exactly? Are you
hearing voices on Pakistani social
media? Are you are you hearing voices
elsewhere? Uh from what I see nothing is
changing in Pakistan unfortunately. I
would love Pakistan to change and become
a civilized nation. Right? Revert to
their roots. But I don't see that
happening. I don't see it happening. You
will always see some people raising
voices against radicalism. Some people
trying to be the voice of reason. There
are always see Pakistan isn't filled
with barbarians right there are good
people too in Pakistan they are a small
minority I'm sure but there are good
people too in Pakistan and they will
probably raise some raise their voices
against all the terrible things that are
happening so you'll see that from time
to time but the majority
is not like that unfortunately that's
the problem I mean I have people from
Pakistan who are longtime viewers of
this H
not a lot but a few and clearly they are
sane intelligent good people right but
unfortunately they are a minority in
Pakistan the majority of Pakistanis are
they hate India they have been taught to
hate India it's not even their fault but
it is what it is right that's why
Pakistan and India are adversaries not
through our
we didn't engineer the situation we did
not okay um Only gems says how did
current civilization went from planes to
moon landing in 60 years and batwash was
not able to do it in for 6,000 years.
Oh so look
there is something called a tipping
point right when everything converges
all the technological advancements
converge and all the right conditions
are present in one part of the world
where sudden technological leaps can
happen and that's what we have seen in
the 20th uh 19th and 20th century. So
how did we go from planes to moon
landing is the question right? The moon
landing it happened because of a number
of technologies not just rocket
technology
but also quantum technologies and uh so
much more.
So in 1900
we did not even know what quantum
mechanics was. Without the knowledge of
quantum mechanics no moon landing would
have happened. none of the present day
technologies would have happened. Um
it's in the early 1900s that the first
aircraft was flown, right? And then by
1969 you had the first moon landing. So
so much progress happened in about 60
years. Tremendous progress. The question
is why was Baratwash not able to do it
in 4 6,000 years. See 1,000 years ago
around 10,000 AD bhat was the most
advanced civilization in the world. 1000
AD Europe was was in the dark ages
right the Islamic uh golden age was
beginning to set beginning to start
around 1000 AD because of knowledge
extracted out of India
so at that time Bat had the most
advanced knowledge structures the
educational system um universities all
of that in India India was a fully
industrialized fully developed and full
fully urbanized civilization all of that
was there.
So we were the most technologically
advanced civilization at that time and
yet
and yet the technology was not advanced
enough. The kind of advancement you had
in Europe in 1900. So in around 10,000
AD the downfall of India as a
civilization starts because of the Turk
occupation and that's where the
education system is completely
destroyed.
Right? So around 100 AD the knowledge
that we had and the systems that we had
had not yet reached that point that's
called a tipping point where suddenly
all these very rapid advancements happen
right if India had not been destroyed
civilizationally in the past 1,000 years
we would have been probably the first to
to uh discover all these things.
Okay. But that's all ifs and buts. It's
all hypothetical because somebody else
made those discoveries.
Puchun says, "Sir, don't you think there
are too many incidental um Don't you
think there are too many incidental
conspiracy theories about the small
hats?
Do you believe in any conspiracies?" Um,
I stay away from conspiracy theories. I
um stay away from things that are based
on speculation and are not grounded in
hard evidence. I mean, if you start
going down those rabbit holes where
people make all kinds of stories and
claims without hard evidence, then I
mean, that's not for me. So, I stay away
from conspiracy theories. There are all
kinds of claims about small hats, big
hats of this hat, that hat, whatever
hat, black hat, red hat, whatever. Uh,
but many of these theories are based on
very flimsy claims that are not backed
by hard evidence. I stay away from that.
So yeah,
Brahmaputra Mosqua says why is vasal
inevitable for us in 3 to 5 years? I
have never said that vasal is inevitable
for us in 3 to 5 years. I've said that
the probability is
high.
It doesn't mean inevitable. Let's say
you have a 60% probability of something
happening. That is not inevitability. It
means there's a 40% probability it will
not happen too. Right? So I have never
said that vasal is inevitable. I've said
that there's a higher more than 50%
probability that India becomes a vasal
of the US in the next 5 years
maybe 60% probability but I am still
optimistic it won't happen please please
when I say something please pay
attention and and and understand the
context and don't just take out one or
two words from it understand exactly the
full thing I'm saying okay it's not
inevitable it is likely the probability
is high but it's not inevitable I am
hopeful Hopefully it doesn't happen and
I'm optimistic it doesn't happen. Okay.
So let's be optimistic shall we?
Mohit Raj Singh is a new member. Thank
you very much sir. Thank you very much
Moit G and welcome to the membership of
the channel. Thank you so much.
Mohitp says is it fair to blame
Emperor Ashok for the fall of Gandhar?
Now when you say fall of Gandhar are you
referring to the fall of Gandhar around
1000 AD? Of
course, that's when Gandhar falls,
right? That's when Gandhar
is no longer part of our civilization.
Uh with the uh rise of the Guri uh
dynasty, the Gurid dynasty which gives
us the monsters eventually like Gori and
then later Gaznavi who was part of the
Gaznavvid Empire. So of so Gandhar falls
around 10,000 AD. Gandhar was the
original Kashmir. The question you're
asking is is emperor is it fair to blame
emperor Ashok for the fall of Gandhar?
I suppose you could blame him.
And then the my viewers will say what is
the Bijit talking about? Ashoke lived
what three whatever 300 AD or somewhere
around that time. Let's say 300 AD. Uh
let's see. Okay. Okay, let's let's see
his uh when did he when did he ru a
shoke the great
Oh, come on. I'm not a robot.
Traffic lights. Oh, bro. Okay, here we
go. Verify.
Ashoke Moria. 268 BC until his death.
232 BC.
So, let's say 250 BC. That's Ashoke,
right? So what is the connection between
an emperor who ru ruled in 250 BC and
something that happened in 1 AD? That's
a gap of 1,200 years.
So how is he to blame? Well, he brought
this
obscure fringe religious movement that
nobody had heard of called Buddhism and
he turned it into a global phenomenon.
Right? Buddhism both the dharma. And
when it comes to Gandhar, 1,000 years
before today, around 1000 AD, Gandhar
was almost well significantly Buddhist,
not entirely Buddhist, significantly
Buddhist.
And large parts of Central Asia were
significantly Buddhist.
And when the Turks
invaded Central Asia, then India,
wherever there was Buddhism, there was
the almost instantaneous conversion of
the populations to Islam.
The Buddhists did not resist Islam. They
converted. The Goris were Buddhists.
The Goris were Buddhists.
They were Indians. They were not Turks.
And what happened? They are the first to
destroy Somnat.
So wherever you had Buddhism, you had
the almost
instantaneous
conversion to Islam. Whenever you had
what we now call Hinduism, there was
resistance. You had Hindus in in in six
in Gandhar in Afghanistan until like a
few years ago
we resisted.
So Ashuk propagated
this new
dharmic flavor that was unable to resist
uh you know conversion to Abrahamic
religions at all. So yeah in a way you
can indirectly blame Ashoke for the fall
of Gandhar. Yes.
A Rahul says almost 23 joined an MNC
bank after undergrad as SDE. two years
scene, I regret it. Corporate politics,
unskilled managers that treat employees
unfairly.
Well, that's that's uh not an unusual
story.
Okay. What's SD? Let me see this. Okay.
Uh SD full form
senior development engineer or
something.
Um software devel Okay. What what am I
talking software development engineer?
Okay. You've joined an MNC bank as a
software development engineer and 2
years in you regretted corporate
politics, unskilled managers. Well,
that's the scene in India. That's the
scene in it in India.
That's how it is. So,
what can I say?
If I were to be harsh on you, I would
say deal with it.
If I don't want to be harsh harsh with
you, I'll still say deal with it.
you are in this now.
Um, obviously the the conditions aren't
optimal.
Politics is the most desperating thing
for for meritorious people. Merritorious
people, people who have who have talent,
people who have some quality in them.
They hate politics because politics is
about bypassing merit merit and talent
and progressing up the corporate ladder
through underhand means that is that is
office politics. Right? So that is the
most annoying and and nasty thing about
corporations but it's there in any
office any corporation you will have
office politics any will of unskilled
managers who treat employee all that
stuff. So my point is look you have
chosen this this this uh particular
career as of now the choice is deal with
the minefield that you're in and excel
no matter what happens find ways of
dealing with it or maybe move to some
other line of work I suppose
um
so this sort of thing you'll find
everywhere even if you move to an
academic job you'll find academic
politics there politics you will never
be able to get rid of it. Wherever you
have a collection of human beings you
will have some form of politics.
Um so what you can do is after if you
have spent two years you have gained
some experience if this place is toxic
move to a different company perhaps. So
find a way find a way. All right sir all
the best all the best. Mohitp says is
polytheism the lack the reason for the
lack of unity among Hindus and Indians?
If so that what's the solution?
What is the reason for lack of unity
among Hindus and Indians? Is it
polytheism?
Is it polytheism?
Wasn't Rome united?
Massive empire. Polytheistic empire.
Did polytheism come in their way? No, it
did not.
So what is the reason for the lack of
unity among Hindus and Indians?
You know when the Americans talk talk
about India and Pakistan they talk
differently right? When they talk about
India about America's relationship with
India they say shared values. When they
talk about their relationship with
Pakistan they say shared interests.
Remember interests always trump values.
The problem for the lack of unity among
Hindus and Indians is that we have too
many groups within India
who have shared interests that are at
odds with the interests of other groups.
We don't have common interests.
We have common values polytheism. Yeah,
sure. But we have groups this cast, that
cast, this region, that region who all
have different interests. Interests that
are clashing with other people's
interests. And these divisions have been
created in India artificially
and these divisions are still being
maybe deepened today by politicians
to create groups who have different
interests from other groups. That is the
reason for the lack of unity.
So how do you unite Indians?
By aligning everybody together and
giving everybody shared interests,
common interests.
Not just common values but common
interests.
For that you need the right leadership.
That is your solution. For that you you
need you need the right leadership.
Okay. Rarun Rajar good to see you sir.
Good to see you back after the Epstein
files. I can totally see them as evil
enough to stop cancer, cure AIDS, cure
etc for profit. I used to think these
are so evil
to be true. After the Epstein files all
the evil has come out in public. these
people the kind of things they do the
the things they do are unspeakable
unspeakable
the more I see this stuff on I have not
even visited the website website of the
Epstein files okay I have not dared to
do that whatever I see is what I see on
my uh ex timeline
time to time some screenshot comes out
of some Epstein email from the Epstein
files and every time I see some one of
these things it's it's more and more
horrifying
absolute monsters
Yeah. So, look, one of the things in the
US is the pharma industry. The pharma
industry is all about profits. It's not
about finding cures. It's about
maintaining patients, keeping them sick
for their entire lifetime. It's about
creating chronic conditions that have to
be treated throughout a person's
lifetime.
If you look at Americans,
every American is is on pills.
Most Indians don't take pills, right?
You may take pills maybe once a year or
once in two years if you are sick if you
have some illness but otherwise on a
day-to-day basis do you take pills you
don't take pills Americans take pills
every day like twice a day or whatever
they're on all kinds of pills
anti-depressants anti this this that
that I don't know what else so everybody
is hooked on all these medicines and
without those medicines they can't
perform they can't function properly
so yeah it looks like cure to cancer
must be easily available but these
people have suppressed
cancer and god knows what other
illnesses. Absolute evil monsters.
Dark side of the moon says proof of ISI
funds uh lashkar a taiba j a muhamad
attacks on India. Uh why does US help
and give aid? Why do it despite ruined
economy? Why no big international
outrage on innocent deaths? So you want
me to provide proof of ISI funding these
attacks on India?
I
proof of ISI funding. I mean isn't it
enough to know that Ajal al- Kasabu came
from Pakistan?
I mean the proof India has given dosi
after dosi to Pakistan and the United
Nations in the US about this.
Why are you asking me for proof about
these things? It's it's everyone knows.
It's an open secret. It's not even a
secret. Everyone knows this what
Pakistan does.
ISIL, LE, JM, they're all part of the
same same thing, same organization
essentially, right? Uh and now why does
the US help and give aid? Look,
the US doesn't give aid. It funds it has
historically funded Pakistan. See, like
this um in 1979, the USSR invaded
Afghanistan. Okay, Christmas Day 1979
was the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan
and the US was very concerned. They did
not want the US USSR to expand their
footprint. So they decided to set up to
to to use Pakistan as a proxy
against the USSR. So they gave Pakistan
various kinds of help. One is
um
um people who are experts in guerrilla
warfare who will train Pakistanis and
Afghans to fight the Soviets using
guerrilla warfare. So the Americans
trained these mujahedines in Pakistan
who were recruited from Madras and
whatnot and from the Afghan population
who had fled to Pakistan. These
mujahedines were recruited from these
from these groups and they were given
training
initially
by Americans. Maybe the Americans
trained the Pakistanis who then trained
the mujahedines. Okay. And then the
mujahedins will need weapons. They
they'll need funding. They'll need
ammunition, arms, all that. All of that
was routed into Pakistan by the
Americans but through third parties.
And that's how the there was this decade
long mujahedin war against the Soviet
occupation of Afghanistan. Eventually
the Soviets had to leave. So after a
decade there were so many mujahedin
camps in Pakistan and so much over
capacity for producing mujahedines.
So after the Soviets leave Afghanistan,
what do you do with this? Divert that
into Kashmir.
And the Americans knew it very well what
the Pakistanis are doing. And maybe the
Americans suggested that. And during the
1980s, the Pakistanis were training all
these sick Kalistthani terrorists
and pushing them into India
and there also the Americans knew and
much of the money and funding in arms
and ammunition was coming through the
same channels that the Mjahans were
getting. Right?
So that's the deal. So why did the US do
this? Why did the US fund and finance
Pakistani terrorism against India?
because the Americans know what India's
potential is
in the uh in the middle of the 20th
century the Americans used to talk you
know some dossier some documents have
come out where they are expressing
concern about India's potential rise
that if India gets its economy right
then India can rise way ahead of
imperial Japan where Imperial Japan used
to be if India gets the right kind of
leadership then this small island of
Japan set of islands the way it rose as
an empire India can dwarf that rise
And India was not aligned with the US.
So the Americans wanted something to
counterbalance India and keep India off
balance always. That's that's Pakistan.
That's why they eventually gave Pakistan
nuclear weapons. Right? And the
Pakistanis why do they do it despite the
ruined economy? The Pakistani generals
and army people do they care about the
Pakistani economy and the Pakistani aam?
They don't care. They simply don't care.
Right? So that's real.
Okay. Subs says Sar was dhananda cruel
and how was he defeated? Danandanda he
is said to have been a very cruel king.
He said to have been a king who taxed
his people very harshly and hoarded all
the money did not use it for societal
welfare for the welfare of the uh of the
of the empire
right and yeah maybe cruel as well in
other ways. So that's the kind of uh
king Dananda was. He was obviously a
very powerful king. It is his massive
military that scared off Alexander
soldiers, right? Dan. So how was he
defeated? Uh
a regime change led by um
um Vishnu Gupta Chanaka and Chundra
Gupta Moria. Chanaka was the brains.
Moria Chandra Gupta Moria was the guy
who actually did this. And what were the
mechanics and dynamics of this? Well,
that's a long story. Even I have not
read this in detail. But yeah, there was
a war.
It was a military campaign in which the
Nanandha was defeated and that's how
Chandra Morya became emperor.
Rahul Lak says, "How did you publish
your books on Amazon? By what method?
Have any become bestsellers? 10,000
plus?" No, I haven't promoted them that
much or something and none of these are
bestsellers. These are not books yet.
These are individual chapters
of what will eventually become a book.
It's just uh you know trying something
out different that's all. How do you
publish it? You can anybody can publish
original works on Amazon. There is
something called KDP right? Amazon KDP.
Look it out. Check it out. uh what you
have to do is you need to have an
original work that you have created
yourself and
and that you if it's you have to format
it in in a certain way and then you have
to upload it to Amazon you to create an
account and do all that and you have to
fill up the form and give a title and
keywords and whatnot and uh and the book
cover and that gets published that's how
it is done
NPS says why physicists get excited
about oldest galaxies like mom D14,
GNZ11, but ignores Milky Way
ancientness. Milky Way is 13.6 billion
years old. Uh, they can study stars here
only and figure out how the first galaxy
is formed. Is the Milky Way 13.6 billion
years old? Um, look, the universe
is 13.8 billion years old. Is the Milky
I've not checked out the age of the
Milky Way. One second. Uh, Milky Way
age. How old is it? 13.6 billion years
old.
Well, that's interesting. Um, it formed
about 2003 300 million years after the
big bang. So, now we are talking about
oldest galaxies like MOS even 4. These
are the oldest galaxies that have been
discovered by the James Web Space
Telescope.
Yeah. JWST.
Now the JWST is discovering these old
galaxies really really ancient galaxies
that are so old that I mean they kind of
uh break the models that we have of the
universe. Uh the the
our understanding of the universe was
that galaxies would not form in the
first couple of 100 million years but
there we have well-formed galaxies.
So the point is this the Milky Way is
let's say it's 13.6 6 billion years old
like it like we saw. But the Milky Way
is a well-formed massive galaxy today.
But when the Milky Way was first formed,
let's say 200 million years into the
into the birth of the universe,
was the Milky Way already wellformed
then? Probably not. Maybe only the seeds
of the Milky Way had formed at the time.
At the time, maybe it was a small mini
baby galaxy.
But when we see these old galaxies, MO
Z14 etc. they are already fully formed
galaxies at 200 million years or
whatever. So let's see the age of MO
Z14. Yeah,
lag. Google is lagging for some reason
today.
MOMZ4 the most distant known galaxy red
shift of 14.44.
It existed only 280 billion million
years after the big bang. And it's
unexpectedly bright and chemically
enriched for its age. The point is it's
already well evolved.
It's not a baby galaxy at 280 million
years after the big bang. It's already a
fully formed, well evolved galaxy. And
that is the issue.
The Milky Way must have been a baby
galaxy at the time. It would not have
been a massive like m4 or the other one,
right? So that's the issue and that's
why this is so exciting and also very
well yeah very exciting and definitely
challenging because it now challenges us
to to reformulate our our our models of
how galaxies form and at what period of
time in the universe's evolution to the
first galaxies form. Clearly we have
evidence that kind of runs counter to
what we understood thus far. So that's
the deal.
Kirmava Jones says, "Are Indians truly
one people with a shared history? If so,
how do we reconcile this with our
entirely unrelated language families?"
See, language families and all, yeah, we
have according to the the consensus
linguistics, we have two language
families, Arian and Travidian, right?
But that's what the colonials taught us
and we have simply continued teaching
that. Have we tried to study linguistics
a priority from the very first
principles all over again without
keeping without incorporating the
colonial baggage?
It is very likely that the so-called
Dravidian and Arian language families
two different language families also had
a shared ancestor
in the subcontinent.
Maybe two groups of people got separated
for maybe several thousand years because
the subcontinent is so large and today
it's open but in the past it was like
the Amazon rainforest. It was so densely
densely forested.
So humans first reached the subcontinent
let's say about 75 80,000 years before
uh before today about 80,000 years
before today. That's the out of Africa
migration. And maybe it separated into
two groups perhaps at some point in time
and they got
they got separated for maybe several
thousand years because of the incredible
forestation of the subcontinent which
you don't see today at all. So today's
subcontinent is not the same as the
subcontinent of subcontinent of 20 30
40,000 years ago. It was way more
forested. It was like the Amazon
rainforest.
So these people clearly had the same
origins but got separated. That is a
very plausible scenario. Has any
historian has any linguist considered
that? Have we tried to go down and find
the deep roots of the so-called
Dravidian and so-called arian languages?
It's very possible that the the roots
are the same,
right? How do you know these language
families are unrelated?
We have never bothered to dive deeper.
Our historians, our linguists remain at
the superficial level deliberately
right
now. When it comes to shared history,
maybe the two groups were separated for
maybe 10,000 years. It's possible for
that to understand that we'll have to
dig deeper into archaeology to to to
levels of soil of straighta soils which
are like 20,000 years deeper or deep 20
30 40,000 years deep. The further you
deep under the soil the the the deeper
the further back you go in time. But we
haven't done that. We haven't done that.
We are looking at something that's 2,000
years old maybe 2500 years old. We don't
dig deeper. Our ASI doesn't care about
that. or maybe they don't have funds or
whatever. We simply don't research our
history.
We don't try to discover new things
about our history archaeologically,
linguistically, culturally, whatever.
Let's say I create a new organization
which is a parallel of the ASI but
professional
and I get funding of let's say $10
billion. I will set up archaeological
projects all across the country, north,
south, east, west. Dig deeper. Dig
deeper. find the truth of how ancient
how old the human presence is in various
parts of India and by that you can find
out if there was a separation for a
certain period of time and I would also
fund a bunch of of linguists
young linguists who will ignore
mainstream linguistics but drill down in
linguistics based on first principles
only and I promise you you'll find
ancient connections between the two
language families
but in India no one does this. Nobody
has the vision. Nobody has the has the
inclination to do these things. And
that's why we are taught that we have
two unrelated language families.
It's a pathetic state of affairs in this
country. Instead of unifying the
country, we seek to divide the country.
We are one people with a shared history,
shared ancestry. Our ancestry goes back
70, 80,000 years in the subcontinent.
But your teachers and your textbooks
won't won't teach you this. Genetics
tells you that. tells you that
Brahma Mosqua says as populations rise
and some attain more are new souls made
the south won't accept Sanskrit as Tamil
developed quasi separately from its
solution the solution is proper is is
high quality leadership today we have
politicians who seek to divide us
we need politicians not politicians we
need leaders
who unite us. That's what we need.
The cholas,
what are their inscriptions in in India?
Tamil and Sanskrit. Outside of India,
all Srit.
When the chasalized
the whole of Southeast Asia, which
language did they
bring to Southeast Asia? Sanskrit. The
chasers are the greatest of Tamils,
aren't they? But today Tamil Sanskrit
Tamil people won't accept Sanskrit. Why?
It's not foreign to Tamil people. It's
their own language. It's our common
civilizational language.
So the solution is
the right kind of leadership which we
don't have today.
As populations rise in some moas are new
souls made. Well, every living being has
a soul, right? Every living being is an
atma. Even a cat has an atma. Even a dog
has an atma, a horse, a cow,
an ant.
So if a if a cat does some good karma in
its life, maybe in the next life it will
attain a higher level of existence and
be and and transition from being a cat
to maybe a human being.
That's the only thing that can explain
the number of human beings we have on
the planet today. A lot of them have
risen from the lower levels and become
newly minted human atmas. That's why the
quality of the population is human
population is so is is is deteriorating
kind of you know
okay
slay says don't don't worry guys hurry
is coming like he had promised well
hurry please hurry up
yeah
I would like to see hurry in my lifetime
I'll be the happiest person
feel strong says are you feeling strong
Man, I always feel strong, man. Should
always feel strong. Strive to feel
strong, work hard to feel strong and
feel strong. Love your um love your the
name display name feel strong man.
Awesome.
Uh Rudra says, "How should we balance
dark tried traits and dharma
on?" How should we balance dark tried
traits and dharma on nation's point of
view? Absolute approach either of it is
disaster. How comes how some can balance
it so great is mind-blowing.
Dark tried traits. Uh what are the dark
tried traits in psychology?
Um narcissism, psychopathy, and one more
right. Um what are the dark tried dark
tried traits?
Uh dark tried traits. Oh, come on
Google. What are you up to?
Um give you a second.
Okay. Narcissism, makaveism and
psychopathy. Okay.
So these are three uh malevolent
subclinical personality traits. Uh
and individuals with high scores in
these traits. So this is psychology,
right? It's a psychological framework,
the dark triad. So the question Rudra is
asking is how should we balance these
three dark triad traits? narcissism,
mavalism and psychopathy and dharma or
nation's POV.
Um
I'm not able to understand how
these psychological traits
have something to do with the nation's
point of view and dharma.
Okay. So if a person has these dark
tried traits, can the person be dharmic?
Well, I suppose if you control yourself,
you can be dharmic. I suppose I'm not
sure. Um,
see if a person has these three traits,
I suppose that person will not be a very
nice person. May perhaps have criminal
tendencies of some kind. I'm not sure
how it works, but okay. So, yeah, that
person will be less likely to be a
dharmic person, I suppose. Yeah, in
every society, in every population, you
will have some people who have these
traits. Hopefully, it will be a
minority, but yeah, you will have people
and some of them will obviously have
criminal tendencies also. Um
yeah so I am not an expert in this
matter so that's all I can say I suppose
that if somebody has these traits all
three uh then they will not be very
dharmic fields strong man says 2008
global crisis was a tipping point for
the rise of China did India miss out
opportunity in 2020 when the world was
locked down or is our pivotal point yet
to come
see China had done the hard work of
fully industrializing by 2008. So when
2008 came, it was able to capitalize on
the opportunity,
right? China had put in the hard work
over decades.
That's why it was ready to seize the
opportunity in 2008. Now what hard work
has India done
in the past few decades? Have we become
a fully industrialized civilization?
Have we become a major manufacturing
power? Are we a major military power?
Are we uh $10 trillion economy? We are
not any of these things as of now.
Right? So in 2020, India for some some
reason decided to lock down the country
along with everybody else. Maybe it made
sense at that time. Nobody knew what
kind of virus this was. Corona virus,
Wuhan 19, Covid 19. No one knew knew at
the time. Maybe it was something uh
maybe it could have been something as
bad as the Spanish flu. That was
devastating, right? So we didn't we
didn't know how bad this thing was. So
that's why we locked the country down
and then we went with the second wave,
third wave and all. I think that was
overdone.
But whatever the government decides,
right? Uh so that's why our economy went
went backwards.
Uh
so the whole world was locked down and
so were we. So I don't think and India
wasn't ready to take over the world or
something, right? India was still it
still is a minor economy only the fourth
largest in the world right now uh not
exactly minor but middling economy
fourth largest
uh so is our pivotal point yet to come I
hope so I hope our pivotal point is yet
to come but we'll have to do a lot of
lot more hard work before we can reach a
pivotal point we'll have to become at
least a $10 trillion economy we'll have
to do make significant reforms
significant reforms
before.
Yeah. So yet to come. Okay.
Bhagya Bhagu says, "Your opinion on
Ambedkar, is he a divisive figure?" My
opinion on Ambedkar is no comments.
Yeah.
Ian says, "Sanskrit Tamil script
discovered in Egypt recently. It was the
Brahi script, right? They call it Tamil
Brahi because it has some some
additional characters. So Brahmy uh
Brahmy uh inscriptions were discovered
in u some royal tomb or something in
Egypt recently and it dates back to
about 2,000 years or so or so before
today. So clearly Indian travelers went
there and wrote something maybe a
dedication to some god or goddess or
something that sort of thing. So it's
it's no nothing surprising Indians were
in Egypt in 2000 BC,
right?
Jatin Kumar says why English kid talk
maturely than Indian kid.
English kids speak in a more mature
manner than compared to Indian kids. Uh
probably because of the of the superior
education system
and the overall millure that you're in.
So for example,
if you watch Indian cartoons for kids, h
the kind of cartoons Indian kids watch,
those cartoons
their their purpose is to create people
with low IQs. If you watch the cartoons
like Chabin,
it is a recipe for creating people. It's
a recipe recipe for lowering people's
IQ.
And I'm sure that this is going to make
lots of people very angry who watch
Chota Beim as children.
I can't stand Chabim.
Okay. So our cartoon, our our cartoons,
our entertainment, they're all recipes
for lowering children's IQ. And you
compound that with the rotten education
system that also lowers children's IQ.
So obviously you'll have children from
other countries who will be more mature
and sound more intelligent and perhaps
be more intelligent than Indian kids.
See
game changer says was adultery present
in Indian society from 500 BC to 1500 AD
all casts included in this question I am
not aware
not aware sir
to know this you would need ancient
records right ancient records maybe
ancient records of legal proceedings or
whatever all our records have been
destroyed
all our records have been destroyed so I
don't know
the shastra does speak about some
punishments for adultery and so on. So
looks like
all deviant behavior such behavior is
also present in Indian society but I'm
sure it was not common place.
So just like every society has a certain
percentage of people who have criminal
tendencies. Similarly every society will
have a certain percentage of people who
will also have adulterous tendencies. I
suppose it must have been there but if
it was definitely not encouraged it was
definitely not glorified it was
definitely not widespread.
A&M says could you please explain the
major attack orchestrated by Israel's
Mossad against
the pager attack.
So uh is this uh
was it was it Hamas?
First of all, let's check that out. I
think it was Hamas, right?
Major attack.
Okay, it was Israel. It was It was
Hezbollah because it was Lebanon.
So, uh Hezbollah is a Lebanese
organization and Hamas is the uh
Palestinian organization. So, these
pager attacks, what was that? So
apparently these um members of Hezbollah
used to communicate using pagers because
they knew that if they use cell phones
their communications can be tracked by
by external actors maybe the US maybe
Israel whatever and USI Israel
coordinates or so so let's use pagers
you know an ancient device a 20th
century device let's use pages to
communicate so they were using pagers
And Israel found out that these people
are using pagers. And apparently the
Isra the Hezbollah people were they had
given a big order of pagers to some
Malaysian or Indonesian or something
company
and Israel infiltrated somehow that
company and
and they they inserted somehow explosive
components inside the pages manufactured
by this company. Maybe it was a company
created by Israel and made it look like
a foreign company or something like
that. Okay. And these pages were where
they they they inserted u explosive
devices in the pages and then in a
coordinated manner all these pages were
were blown up blown up and this uh
killed or severely injured scores of
hisbah operatives. So that was the pager
attack. There was a brilliant piece of
uh counterterrorism or whatever.
Brilliant. Israel is a is brilliant
people and brilliant operations. Mossad
is well legendary for a reason, right?
Sager Gare says, "Could you please list
the invasions of India century wise from
the beginning to the end? Also, could
you mention which territories we lost
and how and in which we were able to
defend overall successes and failures?"
Look, century wise, it's hard to do, but
let me try and do it off the top of my
head. Yeah.
Invasions of India.
So
okay. So
let's start with about 300 AD around
that time.
Do we have something before that
invasion of India? I can't think of any
invasion of India before any major
invasion of India before that.
There were some battles.
Okay. Let's start with Alexander. So
Alexander's attempted invasion of India
327 BC or wherever it is. You can look
up the exact dates. I don't remember
exact dates. Around that time Alexander
attempted an invasion of India. It was a
disaster for him. So that is Alexander.
Um then you have uh the Seucid war
against India which was the army of
Salucus nicator which went to war
against India briefly. It was kind of a
handshake actually. Hi I'm here. And
then India and Greece made an alliance
and we became allies and friends. So
there there was a solucid brief attempt
to invade India half-heartedly. They
didn't really want to do that but
whatever. Uh solucid invasion. Uh then
you have the um
then you have the Greek city states that
small states the bacter gicoactran
kingdoms and indogreek kingdoms as a
consequence of the uh disintegration of
the solucid empire that's northwestern
India including Gandhar and uh
Tajakistan Turkmanistan not Turkman
Tajakistan that region uh then what
happens is uh the skitian invasion of
India India the Indoskeian invasion of
India there was a domino effect the the
the
eruption of the Jonu out of Mongolia
Huns that precipitated the precipitated
the exodus of the Kusans from the Tarim
basin region which precipitated the the
exodus of the Smithians from central
Asia into India a domino effect. So the
schizian invasions of India we had then
the Kushan invasion of India then the
Hunik invasions of India around the
fifth sixth centuries AD right um what
else do we have
the Hunik invasions of India which
eventually succeeded kind of right um
then then you have the Turk invasions of
India starting about then you have bin
Kasim around 800 700 AD 800 AD tries to
invade Sind then succeeds to some extent
bin Kasim Arab. Then around 10,000 AD
the Turk invasions of India start and
that's wave after wave after wave and it
goes on and on and eventually it
succeeds. Um then the then the European
invasions of India
uh in so you have initially Europeans
setting up trading posts and then
starting to take over Indian territory.
So that is European occupation of India
right and then if we look at other parts
of India
early early 19th century the Burmese
invasion of Manipur which led to seven
years of disaster that's also an
invasion of India
um
then 1962 Chinese invasion of India and
I think I think that's about it. I'm
sure I've I must have omitted some minor
things here and there, but kind of
that's that gives you an overview, a
high level overview. All right. Okay.
Dendor says, "Are you into hi-fi audio?"
If yes, your favorite bands. Hi-fi
audio. I'm into music. I love music. I
am kind of a lapsed musician myself. I
still have a bunch of guitars waiting
for me to pick them up. Every few months
I change the strings of the guitar and
play a few play a little bit and then it
goes back and I
Yeah, I should reconnect with music,
shouldn't I? Uh, so I don't know what
hi-fi audio is. Let me Let me look up.
Is that some special kind of audio?
Hi-fi audio.
What's hi-fi audio?
Let's see. High fidelity audio.
Um, yeah, that's high quality music,
right?
Okay. So I am definitely into uh music
being a lapsed musician myself. What
kind of my favorite bands? Well, first
of all, my favorite genre of music is
Indian classical music. Raas
there was a time when I used to when I
used to experiment playing raas on
guitar you know using alternative
tunings not the standard egbe tuning but
alternative tunings. Each raa would have
its own tuning depending on its drone
notes its its uh surren and consonant
note and so on. So Indian classical
music and uh who are the great musicians
of Indian classical music? Uh Pandit
Nikl Banerjee uh Pandit Ravish Shankar
Uh
Hari Prasad Chasia
Palos
um Aliakbar Khan
uh Amjadi Khan Rajan Sajan Mishra
the Dagger brothers so many so many so
many Yamunar
um Beim Jooshi
So so many so many Indian musicians and
Indian classical music is the greatest
genre of music, the greatest system of
music ever invented. But it's dying a
slow death and nobody's even noticing.
When it comes to western bands, yeah,
sure I I don't listen to contemporary
music anymore. It's garbage. It's trash.
It's industrial mass generated music.
But uh the bands of the 20th century
were outstanding. Some of them Led
Zeppelin, Pink Floyd, um Beatles
Beatles, Led Zeppelin, Pink Floyd, two
of the greats, two of the all-time
greats. I'm sure there are many many
more. Uh the Doors, it's an American
band. Um
so many so many. Yeah, I I'm into all
kinds of music. I will listen to music
from
Africa. I listen to music from Mali.
Alifaka
T. Ali, Farcatur, Tumari, Diabate.
Nobody has heard of the names of these
musicians, but I listen to them. Um,
music from Mongolia, The Who. I'm sure
you heard of The Who now? And and so on.
So, yeah, I'm into all kinds of music
and bands.
Ceret says, "It's is it fine to be 100%
sure about assumptions we make in daily
life? I find myself anxious when I am
unsure of something. I've heard
physicist Steven Weinberg said saying I
am absolutely sure of nothing.
So you find yourself an being anxious
when you are unsure of something. See
the the the trick is to think in terms
of percentages.
You can be sure of 100% sure of
everything in in in life.
Okay?
You never know what's going to happen
tomorrow morning.
But you can assign probabilities to
things. So think probabilistically.
That's quantum mechanical thing
actually. No probabilistic thinking. So
I am 99.9% sure tomorrow morning I'll
wake up alive.
So that's a very high probability. I am
maybe 80% sure tomorrow will be a hot
day.
I am 60% sure of something. So think in
terms of probabilities. In that way
you'll be able to manage the anxiety
perhaps better better and perhaps think
of ways of dealing with the other the
the the other situation that may that
may um arise you know or unexpected
situation that may arise. Think in terms
of probability. Think in terms of bets.
What would you bet on if you had to put
money on something? What is more likely
to happen that you you would actually be
willing to put your money on more? Or is
it like 50/50? Is it FE? that that's
another way of thinking.
So yeah, it's about probabilities in
error bars. So how likely is a
probability and what is the um you know
what's the what's the amount of error
that this probability may have. If you
look at things that way, you may end up
with a different way of thinking and
maybe not being so anxious. Okay.
GX KS says, "Leopard spots Mars. Traces
of ancient microlife." Leopard spots on
Mars. Really? Well, that's new. Cats on
Mars. Leopard spots spots
on Mars. Really? What on earth are we
coming to? Leopard spots. What do we
mean by that? NASA's Perseverance
discovered leopard spots on a rock
as potential, albeit unconfirmed, bio
signature,
millimeter sized white spots surrounded
by black rings. Well, well,
okay. So, we have these leopard spots.
These could be potentially bio
signatures is what they say. Yeah.
It's not life on Mars. It it is
potential bio signatures.
And who is this? Okay. Poppy seeds,
leopard spots. Okay. So, this seems to
be similar to bios signatures that we
find in uh fossils on Earth. So, it's
potentially
traces of ancient microscopic life, but
not guaranteed.
So, what do we do to find out? Maybe we
have to transport that rock back to
Earth and then examine it or I don't
know.
Yeah. So, it's not uh it's not certain
that it's a sign of ancient microscopic
life. But looks like we are finding more
and more clues that could potentially
create a pattern that points to
maybe ancient life existed on Mars
perhaps. Let's see. We're in watch.
Uh Dark Orion says, "Sir, you sir, were
you trying to say that India is about
the Gore visit?"
That's a good question you're asking.
There
is India, India is not a vasal. Even if
Gore visits the western whatever the
army base, army command, it doesn't mean
that India is a vasal. It is very
concerning that are we now walking the
door walking the road are we walking
down the road towards becoming vasals.
Let's say see vasal hood is a series of
steps series of actions in it's a
pattern. Let's say we stop buying
Russian oil that is concerning which
means that the Americans demanded we
stop it and we stopped it then let's say
the demand that we will visit this this
army headquarters then we accept that
then maybe we accept something else. So
if we see a pattern over and over and
over again then you would be very
concerned about being a vasal. At this
point in time I'm not concerned about
India being a Wasal but I'm concerned
that we are giving too much access to
the Americans
and this sort of access is unusual.
So I am still at this point in time not
saying India is a vasal and but I'm
concerned that are we are we now
beginning to slowly
give in to their demands
still too early still too early but
concerning
Vive Singh has become a new member thank
you very much Vive Singh G welcome to
the channel's membership I very much
appreciate it thank you sir
Victoria says if we Move all upper casts
from the general category to OBC and put
all and place all the Muslims in the
general category. Then what happens?
What are my what are your views?
Look, it's a nice thought experiment.
Victoria G.
Look, what needs to happen
is remove all all categories of people,
all all casts, all categories, general
category, some non-general category.
Please make everybody the same category.
And if you want to give reservations,
give reservations based on a family's
financial and economic conditions. If a
family is below a poverty line or below
whatever line, then you give them
reservations for maybe 5 years, 10
years, 20 years, whatever, not more than
20 years. And please don't discriminate
based on people's so-called casts or
category or whatever.
The politicians say that we have to
annihilate cast. Cast is a big issue in
India. Annihilate cast. But they have
created a system which solidifies cast
which perpetuates cast.
Let us destroy cast completely. Right?
Annihilate cast. Remove all mentions of
cast from all official documents.
Make people genuinely castless.
That solves the problem.
And then if somebody discriminates based
on cast, put them in jail.
So the solutions are simple, but they
don't want to do it.
Okay. Vive Singh says, "What kind of
reading should students and
working-class folks do to face the brunt
of motivated arian invasion theory talks
in colleges and office spaces with
facts?
What kind of reading could you do?"
Well, unfortunately, there is no
highquality popular, you know,
non-technical, non-scientific book on
the arian invasion theory. I can
recommend one article which can be your
starting point for understanding and and
countering uh these lies. Okay, this
article is here. Um, give me a second.
Arian invasion myth Dava.
So, it's my article from 2017 which set
the whole ball rolling. After that,
everybody started looking into the iron
vision theory.
This article was written in 19 in 2017.
That's 9 years ago. In this article, I
have put across
all the facts. This article is the first
time somebody put across all the facts
from all these different domains of
archaeology, linguistics, mythology, uh
genetics, all of these things together
in one place from from hydrarology, from
geology, all these facts together. Okay.
And I've I have given references at the
end.
So archaeological evidence u
hydraological evidence
uh archaeological evidence genetic
evidence
um
there's more literary evidence from the
Bodhi Sutra. Uh once again more
archaeological evidence
this is uh yeah more of that more of
that genetic evidence mythological
evidence and so much more all of this I
have collected together and I've put it
over here and uh I have put I've given a
bunch of references at the end so the
title of the article is the Arian
invasion myth how 21st century science
debunks 19th century Indology
just Google this you will find it all
right That's what you can begin with to
arm yourself with facts against these
this colonial lies.
All right.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "I saw on
predictive predictive history channel
where professor Jang explained how
Stalin played Hitler in great detail
which eventually led to the massive
industrialization of the Soviets
supported by US."
continued.
He explained multiple possibilities
using game theory. He explained how west
thinks versus Russell, empirical versus
intuitive. Interesting channel. Okay,
sounds really interesting. Uh, thank you
once again for the reference and I
certainly shall check out the channel of
Professor Jang. Thank you, sir.
Next. Riu says freemasonry founded by
Bacon, Francis Bacon. Francis Bacon is
it under the Venetian Empire's influence
aimed to spread early atheism and shaped
the future British Empire's world view.
They aimed to spread early atheism.
Very interesting. Let's check out this
Bacon character. Francis
Bacon.
Francis Bacon. Was it founded by Francis
Bacon?
Uh,
pre-masonry.
Let's see.
Let's find out.
Um,
masonic is a foundational and hidden
influence in the development of
speculative Freemasonry
philosophical all that stuff. Okay.
Interesting. Interesting. Okay. Thank
you very much for this uh very
interesting fact over here. Interesting.
So, its objective was to spread early
atheism and it shaped the future British
Empire's world view. Well, that's
fascinating. One of these days I'm going
to have to dig deeper into Freemasonry.
Well, thank you so much for this
interesting fact here, sir. Viju, thank
you.
Arian Rocking Gaming says, I scored 93.6
percentile in J, but I'm preparing for
Indian statistical institute for pure
math research. ISI Kolkata is it? I
think so. J test speed. Indian
statistical institute undergraduate
entrance tests proof and depth. How do I
explain this difference to my parents?
Okay, you want to explain the difference
between u the testing methodology of the
JE versus the testing methodology of the
Indian statistical institute.
J tests for speed. How quickly can you
solve a bunch of problems and ISI
tests for proofs and depth. So you need
to have depth in your knowledge. You
need to be able to prove, you know,
give proofs for various uh yeah
problems. Prove this, prove that,
whatever. How do you explain the
difference to your parents?
Explain it in terms of I don't know if
there's a good explan good good way of
explaining T20 versus test cricket.
So, let's say how long is the J exam? Is
it 3 hours, 4 hours? What what is it?
It's still a long exam. I'm sure but it
looks at you. It looks at how quickly
you you you solve problems small
problems. So it's like you know playing
a T20 match in cricket but J is about
sorry ISI entrance exam is about proofs
and depth. So it's it's more of you know
yeah deeper preparation clearly.
So maybe you could explain by comparing
one with T20 cricket and one with test
match cricket. Perhaps that's may go
into their heads.
I mean, why can't you just explain the
way you explain over here?
Maybe they want maybe. Yes. So, uh
perhaps that is a is an interesting
appropriate analogy perhaps. Perhaps
what how else would I explain this to
somebody who has no understanding of of
science?
Um,
yeah, I suppose that's what I would say.
That's that's perhaps an appropriate
analogy.
Okay, Din. So, so, um, Arian Rocken
Gaming, all the best. All the best. Do
well. Do well.
Okay. Din D says, "Can we expect Mr.
Abigya Anand on on my podcast, please?"
Who is Abigy Anand? Let me see. Abiga
Anand.
Let us see. Abigy Anand. Who is Abigy
Anand?
Uh official jotisha. Astrology.
Astrology.
Yeah. I I don't understand astrology. I
have no understanding of astrology and I
stay away from things I don't
understand.
So, as you will see, I have never hosted
an astrologer on my podcast and I think
that's a policy I will continue. I I
have absolutely zero understanding of
astrology and um
yeah, so I think Mr. Abigan won't appear
on my podcast. Not I'm I'm sure it's a
he's a fantastic person and so on, but I
have zero zero understanding of this.
So, makes no sense for me to go into
that. Sorry.
Sorry.
Um,
Brahma Mosqua says, "Why is Vasal
probable for us in five years? Within
the next 5 years?"
Why is it probable? That's a good
question. Because of the way the world
is changing, the world is the way the
world is shaping up. because of the way
the Americans are now
exerting
their influence and power in reshaping
the world. It's clear that they are they
they have identified a bunch of nations
that are the targets. Uh Syria is done,
Venezuela is done, Cuba will perhaps be
done, Iran will perhaps be done. So
essentially the entire world has to bend
to America's will.
Okay. Now let's say America you know
takes over all the global sources of oil
apart from Russia and then they force
India not to buy Russian oil then they
then we are completely at at their mercy
unless we discover oil of our own
right there is that
and if they can um so the Americans are
now being nakedly openly imperialistic
see Marco Rubio's recent speech wherever
it
He wants to revive western colonialism
and imperialism
and the US is way more powerful than
India and they definitely want India on
their list of vasals
and they have so many ways and means of
making this happen right
so that's why I say vasal is probable
there's a higher probability of vasalaj
than sovereignty in the next 5 years but
I'm still optimistic
says Sri Lanka just won against
Australia Well, well, Australia lost to
Namibia or something. No, Zimbabwe,
right? Recently,
uh, Enawara, that that tall bowler,
Enawara, whatever his name is. Um, so
the Australians lost to Zimbabwe. They
now lost to Sri Lanka. They're out of
the tournament. What happened to them? I
don't know. Did they eat uh some
dodgy prawns somewhere or something? I
don't know. I don't know. Very strange.
Australia, really?
highly unusual. It's like 1992 all over
again. The 1992 World Cup, Australia was
out very fast.
They defeated India by one run in one of
the matches in 1992. Anyhow, Pratip
Kumar Roy says, "Professor Jang has made
various predictions like Donald Trump
winning with JD Vance being his VP.
He also said Trump was historically
involved with some intelligence guy. He
knows tricks safe from Epstein files."
Professor Jang seems to be really
impressive as a person. Yeah,
interesting.
Thank you so much for for these pieces
of information about Professor Jang. I
will check out his channel. Sounds like
a really interesting gentleman.
Anka Kashab has just just gifted five
Aijit Char memberships. Thank you so
much Ankita G. Thank you so much. So
kind of you and yeah, let me thank you
on behalf of the people who have
received the memberships as well. Thank
you so much Ankita G.
Chanak says your thoughts on barat
following allowing roshield and company
as individual advisor to nse IPO black
rockck with go they are all in epste
major players deep state entering India
for its host USA will be dead concerning
concerning
concerning see I have said there is a
high probability of India becoming
vasalized in the next 5 years are Are we
seeing the signs and symptoms of the
beginning of that? I hope not. But it's
very concerning. I hope not. But I'm
concerned very much so. So what are my
thoughts? My only thoughts are this is
I hope this doesn't become a pattern and
I'm very concerned about this.
Kosian World says, "Is Nepali currency
pegged to the Indian rupees? Does this
make Nepal in Indian vasal to a
significant extent?
Is Nepali currency pegged to Indian
rupees? Let's see
Nepal rupee
INR
pegged
is it pegged to the INR? It's officially
pegged to the Indian rupee at a fixed
rate of 1.6 Nepal is rupees to one
Indian rupee. A policy in place since
regulated by the Nepal rush bank. This
arrangement ensures economic stability,
erases trade and limits exchange risks
despite restricting Nepal's monetary
effect flexibility.
You know what to be very honest this
makes Nepal to a certain extent an
economic vasal of the of India
but it is beneficial for Nepal's economy
because the major financial and economic
transaction transactions Nepal's people
have are with India right we have an
open border we are the same people and
so many Nepalese people work in India
live in India
so it makes sense for this arrangement
to exist. But yeah, you could say that
this kind of to some extent vasalizes
Nepal
to some small small extent small not
major but yeah to some extent it does.
Yeah.
Humanity survive says converting to
foreign religion means becoming zombies.
Well,
it depends on the religion I suppose. Um
if you if you convert to Shinto Shinto
religion the Japanese u traditional
faith or system do you become a zombie
if you become if you start practicing
Shinto I don't think you become a zombie
so look my point is it depends on a
foreign which foreign religion you're
talking about right all religions don't
make you zombies some some may perhaps I
don't know which they are but whatever
Amirup Sharkar says Europeans even in
dark ages seemed practical and
strategic. Despite India's deep
knowledge, they colonized us. Why are we
still so emotional today? See,
everybody in in some sense or the other
is practical and strategic. In the dark
ages, the Europeans were well very
primitive, right? Life was held in
Europe at the time. And they colonized
us despite our deep knowledge. Not in
the dark ages, but uh in the past 500
years when they rose out of the dark
ages, right?
Um
so why are we so emotional today?
We are emotional today because so what
you mean by this is that most Indians
are they they they react emotionally
rather than rationally. Right?
Um it's because we lack the ability to
think critically. Our education system
is has destroyed that part of our
intellect
and that's why we we react emotionally
to everything
to to a lot of things especially to
things we don't understand. So when you
lack
intellectual tools
you will resort to reacting with
emotions and that's why a lot of Indians
are so emotional. We are very emotional
people right?
Okay. Uh wrongwan says wrong one back of
the hand if we can make cavary why not
focus transport aircraft too I think we
should focus on transport aircrafts also
yes
right
we should focus on transport aircrafts
we should focus on all kinds of
different aircrafts we should try and
build everything in an atmar way within
India certainly I agree with you
pratip kumar royes s 1 million lakh
world three and third temple
construction about hea abdu also if they
worship bal we're going to worship Indra
too 1 million on on my channel yeah it
will happen maybe after the after the
third world war yeah YouTube has a has a
certain policy towards my channel so it
doesn't matter it's okay look what we
can't control we don't worry about right
my channel is going to stay for for the
foreseeable future at 951k or something
yeah I can see every subscribers rise
then they come down then they rise then
they come down. So whatever YouTube will
do whatever it does. Um
third temple construction about that's
that's funny isn't it? Uh if they
worship Bal we can worship Indra too.
Well who's stopping us from worshiping
Indra? Do worship whichever god you you
feel inspires you right? We can
certainly resume the worship of Indra if
you want to.
Uh Pratip Kumar says about cicada 3301.
Do we have something similar here? I've
heard of some conspiracy theory called
Sicada 3301 on the internet. I'm not
sure if we have I don't remember what it
is first of all. So let us go to
internet. Sicara 3301
dark web or something was it? I had seen
this a long time ago.
um highly sophisticated oh anonymous
online puzzle
designed to recruit intelligent
individuals with with expertise in
cryptography, steography and data
security. These puzzles released between
2012 and 2014 are considered one of the
most elaborate unsolved mysteries of the
internet age and there are videos made
about this and so on.
Um
okay so yeah this very mysterious stuff
right? Do we have something similar
here? I am not aware of it.
Vihang Kuran says, "Hello, sir. How are
you?" I'm good, sir. I'm good. I'm very
well. I hope you're doing good too. I
recently read the news of discovery of
Tamil Brahi inscriptions in Egypt. Are
there any historical evidence of what
kind of relations were between existed
between India and Egypt? Well, the
historical evidence is the records are
gone. In India, we would have had
records of diplomatic correspondents and
travels and and accounts of travelers
and textbooks and whatnot in our ancient
universities in their libraries. But
everything has been destroyed and also
also in ancient court records of our
kingdoms and empires. But even that is
destroyed. So we don't have any evidence
from our side any records from our side.
When it comes to Egypt again most of the
Egyptian records have been destroyed.
Egypt has lost its own original culture,
language, religion, everything. Egypt
first transitioned from its culture to
Greek culture after the after Alexander
installed Tommy as the governor of Egypt
who then became the king of Egypt. So
then for a while Egypt was under Greek
rule. Then it was under Roman rule after
Julius took over and then eventually it
became Christianized and then it came
under Islamic rule and today Egypt is
Islamic and all the records are gone. So
whatever evidence we have, historical
evidence is only on those from those
inscriptions on walls and the presence
of Indian Zebu cattle 4,000 years ago in
Egypt and so on or only that sort of
evidence we have. We don't have any
records of diplomatic correspondence or
or whatever else. We don't have that.
It's all gone.
Pratip Kumar Roy says predictions about
the future of Bengal in India.
Uh Bengal I don't I I don't make
predictions as such. Um
uh predictions I am I I all I'll say is
that I'm optimistic. I choose to remain
optimistic.
Bengal
I hope Bengal sees much better days.
Yeah. Bengal was a fantastically
developed, incredibly prosperous,
culturally great part of India. Today,
not so much. Right? I hope Bengal sees
great days again. But predictions I will
not make. India's future. Well, I've
said there is a high likelihood of India
becoming vasalized in the next 5 years.
I hope that also doesn't happen. I
choose to remain optimistic. But yeah,
Pratit Kumar Roy says, "Old Cartoon
Network was a gem. Now it's shit." Okay.
I have not seen new Cartoon Network, so
I'm not aware of what's there now. Old
Cartoon Network 20, 25 years ago was
outstanding. Outstanding.
Gear TV says, "First of all, hi, good to
see you." So the question is if a person
loses interest in society, marriage or
starting a family and is solely focused
and interested in gathering as much
knowledge as possible like sort of a
polymath where do you see such a person
leading in life? Well, there are
multiple paths such a person can take.
So let's say a person has lost interest
in society, marriage, uh starting
family. All the he or she wants is to
gather as much knowledge as possible and
that eventually makes you kind of a
polymath. Yeah. Okay.
Where do you see such a person heading
in life?
Well, a person like that can be someone
who is a mentor to people in society,
right? It it depends.
If you are that sort of person, you have
multiple choices. One, you gain a lot
lot of knowledge and then you spread
that knowledge to the world. Maybe you
write books, maybe you do some through
some other means, you spread the
knowledge. One of the way is you mentor
people
because you have so much knowledge, so
much understanding, so much wisdom. Then
you can mentor people. Maybe you can be
a government adviser. Maybe you can, you
know, depending on depending on what you
choose. Of course, becoming a government
adviser is not something you choose. You
have to be really good for that. But
yeah, so you can be a writer, you can be
an author, you can be a mentor. Uh
obviously, you have to make money in
some way, right? So hopefully you have
money also. Otherwise you won't be able
to take this path. So there are multiple
parts in this matter but from from a
practical perspective make sure that you
have a you know reliable source of
income or good savings enough savings
for the rest of your life then you can
take this path.
All right. Rudra says, "My question was
not about person POV at all but about
how India should balance Makaveinism,
absolute pursuit of self-interest
regardless of others versus dharma for
other countries." Okay. Or the the dark
triad you are talking about, right?
Okay.
So the question you're asking is what
should India's approach be? Should India
have a dharmic approach towards other
countries? Oh,
all countries are part of the same
family. uh we will not exploit you, we
will not hurt you, we will not harm you,
we will help you whenever you need
without asking anything in return. Is
that the dharmic approach we should have
towards other countries or should there
be absolute pursuit of self-interest?
See decide understand the rules of the
game first of all let let's say I want
to be dharmic but everybody is a dharmic
then can I play that game the game is
rigged right the game what are the rules
of the game the rules of the game are
the dharmic rules but I am trying to
play a dharmic
approach in that so let's say you have a
football match
in which you want to to play in in a way
that is non-physical contact way, not
doing any fouls, not jostling anybody.
But the other team is all about jostling
you and pushing you down and kicking you
down, then who wins? They win.
So if the umpires allow that sort of
play from them, and if you choose
voluntarily not to have the same
approach against them, then you are
putting yourself at a disadvantage.
So when you talk about dharmic approach,
understand that this is the era called
kalyuga in which the dharmic approach
doesn't work
the makyan approach works. So if you are
a leader of India you should be dharmic
towards your people
your people are your family your
citizens are your family
and everybody else they're fair game
that's how you do it. Vihang Quran says
I am interested in learning a new
language. I am fluent in Hindi, Barati
and English. I know very basic Sanskrit.
What language should I start with? Does
India have good research going with
regards to AI and linguistics? I'm not
sure what research India is doing with
AI. Linguistics we are doing nothing
whatsoever. Yeah. Zero in linguistics.
AI maybe we are doing some research.
Maybe some uh some startups are doing
research in AI perhaps. Yeah. uh I've
heard of uh some new startup recently
that came up and seems to be good. So
there is some uh work being done on AI
in India but definitely not in
linguistics that as far as I know now um
you want to learn a new language you're
fluent in Hindi, Marati and English and
you know very basic Sanskrit. So one
option you have is to go forth with
Sanskrit and learn advanced Sanskrit
that's that would make you like it will
really expand your mind and brain you
know so that's one one thing you can do
maybe double down on Sanskrit and go
from beginner all the way to advanced
that's one thing you can do or if you
want to learn a different language well
first of all decide whether you want it
to be part of the Indo-Uropean language
family or a different language family if
it's part of the Indo-Uropean language
You could learn a bunch of languages you
know take one far is a very closely
connected related language language to
Indian languages right parsy it'll be
very easy to learn if you want to it's
got a different script it's got the uh
Persian script which is the derivative
of the Arabic script or if you don't
want to learn a new script then you can
learn one of the one of the European
languages if you know English then
perhaps German will not be that hard
because German is English is a Germanic
language related to German so maybe
German if you want to learn one of the
Romos languages in the Indo-Uropean
family, maybe French, Spanish or
Italian.
Yeah. Um, if you want to learn a
non-Indo-uropean language, well, you
could learn Japanese, Chinese, Korean,
Swahili, African language, something
Arabic, some people learn Arabic. So,
look, there are plenty of choices,
plenty of options out there. Depends on
you. I can't tell you what to learn.
You, it has to come from inside you, you
know. All right. So all the best. All
the best sir.
Lalit power has gifted one membership of
the channel. Thank you so much Lali G.
Very kind of you. I'll thank you on
behalf of the person who received that
as well. Thank you so much.
Godliness says why US admiral and
ambassador have free run today in our
western command.
Even for the group pictures, US admiral
was sitting in the center and our own
left general in the side. This is not
normal. This is concerning. Like I said
a while ago, concerning
very concerning
the US is not an allied country. The US
is a country that doesn't see India as
an ally or a friend. The US has a has a
policy of containing India containment
policy. The US is a nation that has
funded and financed Pakistani terrorism
against us for decades. The US is a
nation that is currently siding with
Pakistan. They sided with Pakistan
during operation zindu. They took
Pakistan's side. They intervened in the
war and made us stop the operation.
It's not exactly a friendly nation,
right? It's a nation that seeks to
vosalize us and what's happening. Very,
very, very concerning. Very concerning.
Adian has become a new member. Thank you
very much, sir. Welcome to the channel's
membership. Thank you.
Gear TV says, "What's your view on Karna
from the Mahabharat? Do you think he was
superior to or at least equal to Arjun?
Karn was a nasty person.
Karn was a nasty person. He was a friend
of Duryodhan.
He instigated Duryodhan
to go to war against the Pandavs.
He if you read the actual Mahabharat,
you will see that Karna was not a nice
person.
His behavior was poor. He had a nasty
temper.
He was no equal of Arjun.
Arjun had it had had his flaws. Sure,
some flaws. But he was a great warrior.
Karna no karna was no equal of Arjun.
Karna is a negative character in the
Babarat. And some people today are
glorifying Karan Arjun and all that
nonsense. Yeah. To some extent he's a
tragic figure. That's why some people
feel sorry for him. Yeah. But he was the
king of Bangladesh. Sure. He had a bad
childhood. Sure. Okay. But he was the
king of Bangladesh. He turned out well.
And see then see the choices he made.
Karn is a negative character in the
Mahabharat. No superior of Arjun not
even an equal of Arjun.
Let P says
I think deep state knows that such harsh
harsh step will be taken only by Trump.
So they rely on Trump. Now I think deep
state tilts to right or left based on
public sentiment and strong president.
So the way I see it, the deep state uses
presidents as tools. they decide who is
the right person for the right time. So
maybe for from 2020 to 24 Biden was the
right guy or puppet Biden. Puppet Biden
was the right guy. Uh and maybe Trump
made a deal and kissed the ring of the
deep state which is why he was made
president now. So the US president is
simply a tool of the deep state. The
deep state is the bunch of people where
the real power lies. Okay. So I agree
that they will rely on Trump for now
because they want to get things some
things done that Trump can do and Trump
is the right person for doing those
things. Uh and you think that deep state
tilts right or left based on public
sentiment and strong president. The deep
state doesn't give a damn about public
sentiment and the president the
president is a puppet of the deep state
and in the public
they are simply assets and resources.
They don't care about public sentiment.
They decide what public sentiment is
going to be. They engineer public
sentiment. They don't give a damn as to
what the public thinks. They tell the
public what to think. They engineer
public sentiment. All right. That that's
the way I see it. Val G. Okay. Kiki Kiki
Susan says, "Thank you." Well, thank you
so much. Thank you to you as well. Thank
you very much.
U Samr says, "Australia lost as many key
players took retirement." Okay. Okay. I
see. I haven't seen the team composition
of Australia. I know that they lost to
Zimbabwe recently which was strange and
uh many key players have taken
retirement. I see. Okay. I haven't seen
their uh team composition so I was not
aware of it. Anyway, thank you. Yeah,
Dreas Mitra is a new member. Well, thank
you very much Shreas and welcome to the
membership of the channel. Thank you.
Riu says later Adam founded a new
version of Freemasonry including occult
elements. He formed a new organization
called the Bavarian Illuminati. Oh,
Illuminati confirmed.
Uh, and there seems to be some
connection between the Illuminati and
the founders of the United States. If
you see the US dollar note, there's the
Illuminati confirmed theme there as
well, right? So, looks like there are
these deep subterranean connections all
over the world which connects the
Freemasons to perhaps the Knights
Templar.
to the Illuminati. Yeah. The Bavarian
Illuminati which was a real thing and
there is some connection with the
founders of the United States. George
Washington is supposed to be have been a
Freemason.
Very interesting stuff. Very
interesting. So thank you for this this
new revelation for me at least. Thank
you.
Pishma says Sar do you think some
threeletter agencies may hypothetically
allegedly perhaps may or may not have
been an eye on you? Does it scare you?
Um, it's possible. Uh, it's possible.
Does it scare me? No. No. I mean, it's
you do your thing. Don't worry about the
rest. Doesn't scare me. I I don't think
I do anything that in any way hurts
them. Right. Do they have their eye on
eye on me? It's possible they may,
right? It's possible because I'm pro-
India and I'm kind of a public figure
and I'm kind of
um teaching Indians common sense and
and critical thinking and opening
hopefully people's eyes to where the
world re the way the world really is. So
I suppose they some of them may have
their eyes on me. It's all right. It is
what it is.
Hanish Sharma says one can learn Krav
Maga at home simply watching or learning
from YouTube. I think you can learn the
basics
you know footwork etc. You can learn the
basics uh when it comes to
various patterns of self-defense and
movement basic stuff you will need a
partner to to do that with somebody
but eventually you will have to join a
dojo or some kind of a school.
Eventually you can learn the absolute
ground level basics from YouTube basic
absolute basic stuff but eventually
you're going to have to join a school or
or a class or something.
Um Hanisha says my father watches you
and every time he watches you he says
why is this guy not in government? He
should he could do so much better. He
sends his love. Thank you so much Hanish
Sharma G's father. Thank you so much
sir. Uh it's very kind of you and I'm
blessed to have your blessings. Thank
you so much sir. Thank you.
Okay, that brings me to the end of all
the questions. It's been almost four of
us once again. So, thank you so much
everybody. It was an unusual live stream
on a Monday, Monday evening for us here
in India. But thank you so much for all
your questions as always. Keep okay,
there's one more question that's come
in. Let's take this one. Hopefully the
last one for today. So CIA retired guy
said at CIA they could convert the
speaker in smart TV into a mic and
listen what's happening in the room.
This is something he has been allowed to
say. I wonder what else he the CIA could
do. The CIA can do all kinds of stuff
that we can't even imagine. Okay,
understand if you have a smartphone with
you,
it's always listening to you. Okay, I am
aware of it. I know it's listening to me
right now. I know that. So it listens to
your most intimate con conversations and
whatnot. Your deepest thoughts, not
thoughts but conversations. Your TV is
listening to you. All smart devices are
looking listening to you. Maybe they are
even watching you. We don't know.
Maybe they can even uh read your brain
waves and thoughts perhaps. I don't
know. Anything's possible. So be
careful.
Um humanity survive says uh converting
to uh these two religions is becoming
zombies. All right. Sir, if that is what
uh you believe, sir. All right. I could
not possibly comment about this.
Okay, that brings me to the actual end
of this live stream. Thank you so much
everybody for the questions for your
viewership. I really really value that
and appreciate that. Thank you so much
once again and I look forward to seeing
you in the next live streams at the end
of this week. Until then, keep learning,
keep raising your standards, keep asking
questions, take care everyone. See you
very soon. Bye-bye.